<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjy Stanton</title>
    <description>UX/UI Designer. Family Man. Music Snob.</description>
    <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 21:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 21:13:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great service (design) at Premier Inn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m always impressed by the good service that me and my family get at Premier Inn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed at one in Portsmouth last summer. I made a list of all the little things that helped make the stay that little bit better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-little-touches&quot;&gt;The little touches…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nicely decorated lobby and rooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;clean and free of clutter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;friendly, happy, helpful staff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;staff that made polite conversation (“good morning” or “how did you sleep?”) for some reason this is tricky to get right in the UK&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;well designed posters, flyers and menus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working air conditioning in the room&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no quick and dirty posters made by staff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;comfy bed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12 o’clock checkout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nice food at breakfast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kids eat free&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;staff sat us down quickly in the restaurant and said we could settle up the bill on way the out (handy when you have kids)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 for 1 drinks at the bar (handy when you have kids)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-aint-the-ritz&quot;&gt;This ain’t The Ritz&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the little touches add up to make a pleasant experience. We don’t need (or expect) five star treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premier Inn know they ain’t The Ritz, and they’re okay with that. They specialise in not being The Ritz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They understand their customers well, and give them just what they need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/great-service-design-premier-inn/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/great-service-design-premier-inn/</guid>
        
        
        <category>service</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Usability research labs in the UK</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve started a list of research labs in the UK. These locations are great for running usability tests. Perfect if you’re a UX designer or researcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list is hosted on GitHub, so please get stuck in and make some improvements if you can…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benjystanton.github.io/usability-labs/&quot;&gt;A list of usability research labs in the UK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benjystanton/usability-labs&quot;&gt;The repo on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/usability-research-labs-uk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/usability-research-labs-uk/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tools for recording usability tests</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Good old Twitter… I asked my friends to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton/status/690206840827834368&quot;&gt;recommend screen recording software&lt;/a&gt; (specifically for recording usability tests), and I got a list of great looking apps to try. Silverback was the clear favourite, although the latest version appears to be in private beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://silverbackapp.com/&quot;&gt;Silverback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201066&quot;&gt;Quicktime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/viewport/id953817966&quot;&gt;Viewport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lookback.io/&quot;&gt;Lookback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://validately.com/&quot;&gt;Validately&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/&quot;&gt;Open Broadcaster Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telestream.net/screenflow/overview.htm&quot;&gt;Screenflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ambrosiasw.com/utilities/snapzprox/&quot;&gt;SnapzProX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I miss anything?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/tools-for-recording-usability-tests/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/tools-for-recording-usability-tests/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>tools</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When things get tedious</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an on-going debate around whether or not designers should know how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My feeling is that we should know enough to be able to tweak things in DevTools and create simple prototypes in HTML, but that we shouldn’t worry about writing production ready stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-tools-are-for-sketching&quot;&gt;Design tools are for sketching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to remember that design tools (like Photoshop or Sketch) are for lo-fi sketching. Even highly detailed mock-ups can never really be considered high fidelity, because they lack the responsiveness and interactivity of HTML and CSS. They can never be truly finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing mock-ups is an incredibly useful part of most projects for me. But there is usually a point where they become tedious to maintain. Pixel perfection is impossible, but that doesn’t mean that visual finish isn’t important. Typographic hierarchy, measure, whitespace and grid ratios are. These are very tricky to control if you don’t know at least a little CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-things-get-tedious-switch-to-code&quot;&gt;When things get tedious, switch to code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain tasks become very repetitive or even difficult when using traditional design tools. Things like…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mocking up the same page at different sizes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;styling up generic pages that could be built from existing components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;making small changes to existing pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;explaining interactions and animation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s a designers duty to recognise this and make sure they aren’t spending too much time on things that could be done better in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-photoshop-not-sketch-either&quot;&gt;Not Photoshop, not Sketch either&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know a lot of designers hope that one day a tool like Photoshop will be able to automatically export good HTML &amp;amp; CSS. I can’t see that happening, but tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.invisionapp.com/&quot;&gt;InVision&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.chrome.com/devtools&quot;&gt;DevTools&lt;/a&gt; are getting closer and closer to becoming what we need. Even if they don’t look like traditional design tools at first glance.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/when-things-get-tedious/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/when-things-get-tedious/</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>tools</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Goodbye WordPress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks the day that I’ve finally switched my blog over from WordPress to &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll’s Website&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordPress has served me very well over the years but I wanted something a little simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reasons I prefer Jekyll are…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can write in MarkDown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it uses Sass by default&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can do everything locally first&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it’s easy to sync everything with GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the templating system is simpler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…which allows me to design more complex layouts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/goodbye-wordpress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/goodbye-wordpress/</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the best way to learn UX?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine asked for ideas on learning UX , so &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton/status/581882786790928385&quot;&gt;I turned to Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and got a couple of really great responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Leisa Reichelt hinted at on Twitter; UX is a broad term and it can mean slightly different things to different people (usability, wireframes, user research, interaction design, HCI etc). Nevertheless, these resources should help you if you are just starting out (or even if you’re not)…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leisa-reichelt&quot;&gt;Leisa Reichelt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/leisa&quot;&gt;Leisa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;s&gt;is&lt;/s&gt; was the Head of User Research at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;Gov.uk&lt;/a&gt; at the time, and she gave me a huge list of resources to look at…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://userresearch.blog.gov.uk/2015/03/18/so-youre-going-to-be-a-user-researcher-top-tips-to-get-you-going/&quot;&gt;So, you’re going to be a user researcher: top tips to get you going&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://userresearchmethods.hackpad.com/Books-that-we-recommend-LChcIQRffI2&quot;&gt;Books that we recommend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://userresearchmethods.hackpad.com/Training-and-education-for-User-Research-bzr9JUSdv2B&quot;&gt;Training and education for User Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andy-budd&quot;&gt;Andy Budd&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andybudd&quot;&gt;Andy&lt;/a&gt; is a User Experience Designer, partner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://clearleft.com/&quot;&gt;Clearleft&lt;/a&gt; and curator of &lt;a href=&quot;http://2014.dconstruct.org/&quot;&gt;dConstruct&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://2015.uxlondon.com/&quot;&gt;UX London&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy recommend this &lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/education/user-experience-design&quot;&gt;User Experience Design Course&lt;/a&gt; by General Assembly in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zachinglis&quot;&gt;Zach Inglis&lt;/a&gt; too for pointing me in the right direction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 20:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/whats-the-best-way-to-learn-ux/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/whats-the-best-way-to-learn-ux/</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding work and managing money as a freelancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been freelancing this time around for just over a year, but in total, I’ve been self employed for over 4. I think that having been self employed on 2 separate occasions has given me an interesting perspective on what works and what doesn’t. This is a round-up of how I find new work and how I manage the money side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-work&quot;&gt;Finding work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 3 regular clients that give me 90% of my work. All of these clients are people that have I have worked with closely in the past. Luckily, this has meant that I haven’t had to ‘go out’ and find more work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However this tells me that I need to build up more long-term relationships with people, if I want a hope of getting new clients in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;networking-with-a-small-n&quot;&gt;Networking with a small ‘n’&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t like the term networking. I went to some proper Networking things when I first started out. The organiser actually said the word “Synergy” so I never went back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Networking (with a capital N) sucks, in reality though, you do need to network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog, speak at meet-ups, help people on Twitter who ask for help. Doing all these things can help grow your network of contacts, and people will then help you in return. Just share what you know, don’t worry about being an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Work hard. Don’t be an asshole. Share what you know.
—&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brad_frost/status/450619808795885569&quot; title=&quot;Brad on Twitter&quot;&gt;Brad Frost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first go self employed, tell as many people as you can. Tweet about it, share it on Facebook, tell your Nan. You never know where work will come from… and in my experience, people like to help you out when you are just starting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;love-thy-client&quot;&gt;Love thy client&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to work really hard for my clients. Not only do I want to do a good job for them. But I want them to recommend me to other potential clients. Given that it can be hard to get new clients… hang on to the good ones that you have. Find ways to show them that you care about their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-out-and-find-work&quot;&gt;Go out and find work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tweet that you are looking for work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask local agencies if you can pop in for a coffee (don’t give them the hard sell)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.workingnomads.co&quot; title=&quot;A curated list of remote jobs&quot;&gt;Working Nomads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://needhq.com/&quot; title=&quot;Apply as a freelancer to receive job notifications&quot;&gt;Need&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;money-business-tax-etc&quot;&gt;Money, business, tax etc.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;being-self-employed&quot;&gt;Being self employed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registering as self employed is very easy and you can do it via The HMRC website. One day, I intend to go VAT registered and become a Limited Company, but for now self employment suits me fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hang-on-to-paperwork&quot;&gt;Hang on to paperwork&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have just left your job, hang on to your pay slips and P45. In fact, just keep every bit of paper from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;saving-for-your-tax-bill&quot;&gt;Saving for your tax bill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every month, I aim to ‘pay myself’ a regular amount of money. In reality this means transferring money from my business account into my personal account. I then keep a portion of this aside in a savings account, ready for my tax bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;banking&quot;&gt;Banking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a separate bank account is a really good idea. I found that using Lloyds (because I do my personal banking with them) was the quickest and easiest was to setup a business account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most business accounts tend to have a ‘free banking’ period (around 12 months) where they won’t charge you for transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-freeagent&quot;&gt;Use FreeAgent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FreeAgent is a simple accounting tool that helps you to track your time, send invoices, log expenses and fill out your tax return. I can’t recommend it enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://fre.ag/43iztqfq&quot;&gt;my FreeAgent referral link&lt;/a&gt; and we’ll both get 10% off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-to-charge&quot;&gt;What to charge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the handy &lt;a href=&quot;http://ournameismud.co.uk/fraq/&quot;&gt;UK Freelance Rates Calculator&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cole007&quot; title=&quot;Cole on Twitter&quot;&gt;Cole Henley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-business-insurance&quot;&gt;Get business insurance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having business insurance helps me to sleep at night. I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://insurancebyjack.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Insurance by Jack&lt;/a&gt; to sort my policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expenses&quot;&gt;Expenses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Record all your expenses. In most cases, I receive invoices via email (for Adobe Creative Cloud, FreeAgent, hosting etc.) which are easy to save for later. If you are buying things when out and about, make sure you keep the receipt (you can claim expenses on things you pay for using cash and personal cards too). Keep a note of mileage, travel costs and house bills too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps with some of the questions that you may have about going freelance. If you have questions… feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton&quot; title=&quot;Benjy on Twitter&quot;&gt;tweet me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 22:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/finding-work-and-managing-money-as-a-freelancer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/finding-work-and-managing-money-as-a-freelancer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>conferences</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>freelance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reasons&amp;#58; London</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This a quick write up of my experience at &lt;a href=&quot;http://reasons.to/&quot;&gt;Reasons:London&lt;/a&gt; this weekend (Friday 20th February).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://lso.co.uk/lso-st-luke-s&quot;&gt;venue was beautiful&lt;/a&gt; and at lunch time we went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.co.uk/biz/whitecross-market-london&quot;&gt;Whitecross Market&lt;/a&gt; for some great street food (it’s worth a trip in itself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drove from Swansea, so we parked in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncp.co.uk/find-a-car-park/car-parks/hounslow-west-stn-lul/&quot;&gt;Hounslow West NCP&lt;/a&gt;. It’s really cheap and easy to drive to, but beware… some of the car park becomes a market on Saturday morning. We found this out the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harry-roberts&quot;&gt;Harry Roberts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry opened with a fairly technical look at Sass techniques for building modular CSS. Specifically for when building websites that allow certain levels of customisation and theming. He looked at ways to balance performance with pragmatism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/csswizardry&quot;&gt;@csswizardry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://csswizardry.com/&quot;&gt;csswizardry.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/csswizardry/4half-methods-for-theming-in-s-css&quot; title=&quot; 4½ Methods for Theming in (S)CSS&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stefanie-posavec&quot;&gt;Stefanie Posavec&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stef is a data designer who has worked on some really beautiful projects for clients like Facebook and the Southbank Centre. She opened by talking about an old episode of Newsnight where they covered infographics. Weirdly I remembered this exact episode… I even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.benjystanton.co.uk/blog/bbc-newsnight-talks-graphic-design-info-graphics/&quot;&gt;blogged about it at the time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She called for designers to move on from infographics… using her amazing work as an example of what is possible when you push yourself to come up with original work based on data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stefpos&quot;&gt;@stefpos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stefanieposavec.co.uk/&quot;&gt;stefanieposavec.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;james-hall&quot;&gt;James Hall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Hall had a rather sobering (but really entertaining) round-up of security issues. TLDR:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t use public wifi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t use internet banking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t build websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… all these things are just too insecure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mrrio&quot;&gt;@MrRio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://parall.ax/&quot;&gt;parall.ax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anna-dahlstrm&quot;&gt;Anna Dahlström&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna had a really good round-up of thoughts regarding designing for new devices, especially when looking ahead to wearable tech and internet of things things (AKA &lt;a href=&quot;http://seb.ly/st4i-stuff-that-talks-to-the-interwebs/&quot;&gt;STTTTI&lt;/a&gt;) like the Apple Watch. She introduced me to the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;http://globalmoxie.com/blog/index.shtml&quot;&gt;data rash&lt;/a&gt; — a kind of eruption of notifications that is becoming more visible and distracting, the more devices we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/annadahlstrom&quot;&gt;@annadahlstrom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annadahlstrom.com/&quot;&gt;annadahlstrom.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/annadahlstrom/reasons-london-beyondthehamburgermenu20feb2015&quot; title=&quot;Beyond the hamburger menu&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andrew-clarke&quot;&gt;Andrew Clarke&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy called for web designers to take inspiration from advertising, by reviving the role of the art director. He argued that the recent focus on process and tools had lead teams to overlook the kind of creativity that can often lead to truly original designs. Oh yeah, there were apes too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Malarkey&quot;&gt;@Malarkey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/&quot;&gt;stuffandnonsense.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elliot-jay-stocks&quot;&gt;Elliot Jay Stocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elliot’s talk was a bit of a retrospective of his work, mixed with tips on designing with grids and running an ethical business. It was a lot to cover, but very entertaining and one of my favourite talks. He recommended the experience of working with friends (and even loved ones) and the virtues of always &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elliotjaystocks.com/blog/pay-your-contributors/&quot;&gt;paying your contributors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elliotjaystocks&quot;&gt;@elliotjaystocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elliotjaystocks.com/&quot;&gt;elliotjaystocks.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 21:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/reasonslondon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/reasonslondon/</guid>
        
        
        <category>conferences</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My top albums 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love music and I love having the time to explore weird and wonderful new albums. Being a freelancer, music helps to keep me company, keeps me focused and lifts my mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.last.fm/user/benjystanton&quot; title=&quot;Benjy Stanton on Last.fm&quot;&gt;my Last.fm profile&lt;/a&gt;, these are my top albums for 2014 (with Spotify links)…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/0bfdoENsRuAz86QNfSaMOx&quot; title=&quot;At Best Cuckold on Spotify&quot;&gt;At Best Cuckold&lt;/a&gt; by Avi Buffalo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/6TbkWAqqY4nhQnYim61IU8&quot; title=&quot;This Is All Yours on Spotify&quot;&gt;This Is All Yours&lt;/a&gt; by Alt-J&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/30zCWpQv7uwfBlQ9UjkqLb&quot; title=&quot;The Night Is Young on Spotify&quot;&gt;The Night Is Young&lt;/a&gt; by The 2 Bears&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/1iVB81BMYrXZiNtzYY3vTg&quot; title=&quot;The Scenic Route on Spotify&quot;&gt;The Scenic Route&lt;/a&gt; by Panacea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/1dKh4z5Aayt8FFDWjO5FDh&quot; title=&quot;Singles on Spotify&quot;&gt;Singles&lt;/a&gt; by Future Islands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/3TQE2fU2KcyjCFutQ2dq2i&quot; title=&quot;Wooden Aquarium on Spotify&quot;&gt;Wooden Aquarium&lt;/a&gt; by Mazes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/5LOVEXnGFLMChzdUNRWRpB&quot; title=&quot;They Want My Soul on Spotify&quot;&gt;They Want My Soul&lt;/a&gt; by Spoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/4jLLt8pqzGxWZ8waNX8ylJ&quot; title=&quot;Our Love on Spotify&quot;&gt;Our Love&lt;/a&gt; by Caribou&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/6IH6co1QUS7uXoyPDv0rIr&quot; title=&quot;Jungle on Spotify&quot;&gt;Jungle&lt;/a&gt; by Jungle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open.spotify.com/album/44ErjiiG1YiiRFMZQL7De2&quot; title=&quot;Keep Moving on Spotify&quot;&gt;Keep Moving&lt;/a&gt; by Hyde &amp;amp; Beast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 13:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/my-top-albums-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/my-top-albums-2014/</guid>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Responsive HTML email talk at Winter LocalHost 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk was an a overview of the way I create responsive HTML emails, covering design, build and most importability testing (at &lt;a href=&quot;http://port80events.co.uk/event/winter-localhost-2014/&quot; title=&quot;Winter LocalHost web page&quot;&gt;Port80 Winter Localhost 2014&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/benjystanton/responsive-html-email&quot; title=&quot;My slides on SlideShare&quot;&gt;Check out my slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 21:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/responsive-html-email-talk-at-winter-localhost-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.benjystanton.co.uk//blog/responsive-html-email-talk-at-winter-localhost-2014/</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>email</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
