<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjy Stanton</title>
    <description>UX Designer. Family Man. Music Snob.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 12:04:35 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 12:04:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Disney data</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;driving&quot;&gt;Driving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swansea to Disneyland Paris and back again - 979 miles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monday 20 March, 15065 steps, 6.94 miles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuesday 21 March, 19831 steps, 9.14 miles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wednesday 22 March, 14818 steps, 6.8 miles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thursday 23 March, 10006 steps, 4.6 miles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rides&quot;&gt;Rides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ride name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Park&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time spent queuing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;time of day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thrill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast pass used?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rides-1&quot;&gt;Rides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small world 0 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tea cups 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dumbo 15&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peter Pan 10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thunder mountain 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thunder mountain 30&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinocchio 30&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snow White 25&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haunted mansion 20&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Star tours 20&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buzz light year 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-3&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aladdin 15&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slinky 10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ratatouille 30&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soldiers 30&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cars 10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crush 60&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aladdin 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-4&quot;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carousel 0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tea cups 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Princess 60&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small world 10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tower of terror 45&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/disney-data/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/disney-data/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My 12 year quest to get a public service design job</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/walter-and-muppets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walter and The Muppets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a lot of “I’m leaving government posts” recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels a bit weird because I’ve been trying for years to get in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I had a master plan, but looking back there were some interesting moments that lead me here. So here goes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-design-job&quot;&gt;My first design job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started in design, back in 2004, I remember worrying that being a designer was a soulless profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents were both in healthcare. And there I was; designing little websites and putting client’s logos on promotional mugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I failed to see how I was helping to make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was something about web design that drew me in though. I started to get excited about the open source movement, and how the web enabled anybody to publish and share content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;public-services-designed-without-designers-gasp&quot;&gt;Public services designed without designers (gasp!)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of jobs and I was working at a branding agency. We were conducting stakeholder interviews with a Welsh public sector organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were showing us their latest software and it was painfully obvious that there were no designers working with their teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They just didn’t see design as something that should be integrated into the software development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It freaked me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were services that I might need to use one day. I could see that they weren’t following any kind of usability or web standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I had the skills to help, but I had no idea how to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;government-digital-service-gds&quot;&gt;Government Digital Service (GDS)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily there were a bunch of people who were figuring it out for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GDS was starting to make a real buzz in the web design community and I instantly fell in love with their world of design principles, service standards and laptop stickers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something clicked, and I realised that I could be a “web” designer and still do work that matters. I just needed a way for a massive public sector organisation to hire me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I didn’t want to move out of Swansea. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comrade-paul-pod&quot;&gt;Comrade Paul Pod&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while later I was freelancing and I came across a tweet by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paulpod&quot;&gt;Paul Pod&lt;/a&gt;. He was looking for user experience (UX) people in South Wales to join him at DVLA. We met a couple of times and chatted about the possibility of me working with him. For one reason or another it didn’t really go anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think often, the easiest way to get into these types of roles is to be contracted in as part of a big external software agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leadin-and-dvla&quot;&gt;Leadin and DVLA&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As luck would have it, &lt;a href=&quot;http://leadin.fi/&quot;&gt;Leadin&lt;/a&gt; (a Finnish service design company) were establishing themselves in the UK with Swansea as their base. They’d won a contract with DVLA and hired me to work with their other UX designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about a year I worked at DVLA as a Leadin employee. With the support of Leadin and Paul Pod, I got to grips with working in government on digital service design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became hooked on the ways of working that GDS helped introduce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;user needs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;designers working in agile teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rapid prototyping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;design patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;laptop stickers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was addictive. I realised that somehow, I needed to keep working in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;matt-jukes-talk-at-design-swansea&quot;&gt;Matt Jukes’ talk at Design Swansea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Matt Jukes&lt;/a&gt; speak at Port80 back in 2014. Little did I know back then that I’d end up working on the new website he’d helped to launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I asked him to speak at Design Swansea (a meetup that I help organise). He gave his &lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/product-is-a-team-sport-c50d234745e#.g3eauj6qu&quot;&gt;product is a team sport&lt;/a&gt; talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He painted a picture of the culture at ONS, especially within the digital publishing department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He spoke about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the digital publishing department’s principles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;taking time to hire the right people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;posters on walls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blogging and working in the open&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;also, he brought laptop stickers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this stuff rang true for me, and I remember thinking that I really wanted to work there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months later they posted a job, I had to try applying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;joining-ons&quot;&gt;Joining ONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve been at ONS for about 4 months now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with service manager &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mr_dudders&quot;&gt;Andy Dudfield&lt;/a&gt; and his team in the digital publishing department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it so great? It combines the best bits of all my previous jobs and more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I get to work with a talented, engaged team … on stuff that matters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the work is constantly challenging and the standard is high&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we are encouraged to work in the open and share what we do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nobody is micromanaged or forced to do overtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… and there are loads of laptop stickers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/my-12-year-quest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/my-12-year-quest/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ons</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Retrospective (my first 2 months)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been 2 months since I started at ONS (Office for National Statistics). Generally speaking, I’m pleased with how I’m doing. I’m excited by the work and the team are great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick retrospective that I’m going to turn into my New Year’s resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-doing&quot;&gt;Keep doing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feeding research findings back into the design process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working with the team to design and iterate together&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Met with lots of people and teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogging (although this has slowed down)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing in the open (again, could do more)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting design evidence from a range of sources (analytics, surveys, usability testing, subject matter experts and lessons learned from previous projects)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show and tells, stand-ups and team walls are working well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;need-to-improve&quot;&gt;Need to improve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need an improved research rhythm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need to recruit more users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m getting stressed out by the competing priorities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need to be better at switching contexts, focus on one task at a time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need to accept criticism without taking it personally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need to break for lunch and eat properly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need more exercise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Falling behind with training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;actions&quot;&gt;Actions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;research-rhythm&quot;&gt;Research rhythm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work even more closely with researcher to make sure we get more momentum in our research schedule. Try more varied research techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-from-home-more&quot;&gt;Work from home more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try working from home on the first Monday of every sprint. This way I can do the school run. Plus catch up on emails, training and writing blog posts. Anything that requires peace and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototype-in-code&quot;&gt;Prototype in code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iterating designs on paper and in Sketch app is working well, but InVision prototypes are too limited to test everything. Easier to re-use code than clickable prototypes. It’s hard to design for accessibility and control things like URL names in InVision and these things are important to the overall user experience. This work should all contribute to the elements and patterns library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;manage-business-as-usual-work-better&quot;&gt;Manage “business as usual” work better&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of small projects that fall outside of the main work I’m doing. I could facilitate meetings with business areas so that we quickly sketch design solutions there and then. I need to come away from meetings with a clearer idea of what I need to design. The team need a clearer idea of what I’m planning to do. I need to keep track of this work somehow on the “business as usual” board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-for-walks&quot;&gt;Go for walks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try going for walks at lunchtime. Find out how to get into grounds of Tredegar House.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/retrospective-my-first-2-months/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/retrospective-my-first-2-months/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
        <category>ons</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User experience (UX) designer objectives</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re working on some objectives for the UX design role at Office for National Statistics (ONS). These are pretty high level, and soon they’ll have specific tasks under each. The tasks will help guide me and the other UX designers, and will be used as a way to monitor performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A well timed visit to the Government Digital Service (GDS) to discuss the role of designers in government has really helped to sharpen up our thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this look like a UX designer to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ux-designer-objectives&quot;&gt;UX designer objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow a user centered design approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use evidence to inform design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create prototypes and iterate designs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work as part of an agile team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be part of the community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communicate effectively&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn new skills and improve existing ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be interested in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-skills/&quot;&gt;post about UX designer skills&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-objectives/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-objectives/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
        <category>ons</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User research activity cards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/paper-prototyping.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paper prototyping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GDS (Government Digital Service) have created this lovely set of user research activity cards. I spotted them stuck up on the wall at ONS (Office for National Statistics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little bit of poking around online, I found the original file. So here’s the link and a round-up of the activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alphagov/govdesign/blob/master/Cards_User_Research_Activities.pdf&quot;&gt;Download the GDS user research activity cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;activities&quot;&gt;Activities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guided tour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pop-up research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sketch your idea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conversation cards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social network mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Affinity mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Card sorting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think aloud&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write a diary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In their environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Map your use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A day in the life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User persona&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paper prototyping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My user journey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remote research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/user-research-activity-cards/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/user-research-activity-cards/</guid>
        
        
        <category>research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Work with me at Office for National Statistics (ONS)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished my second week at ONS. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ons.digital/2016/10/21/my-first-week/&quot;&gt;read about my first week on the ONS Digital blog&lt;/a&gt;. My second week was spent kicking off a big new project, more about that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;were-hiring-designers-and-researchers&quot;&gt;We’re hiring designers and researchers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ONS are currently on the look out for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512692&quot;&gt;2 user experience (UX) designers&lt;/a&gt; and a few &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512654&quot;&gt;user researchers&lt;/a&gt;. The roles are based in either Newport or Titchfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-ux-designers-do&quot;&gt;What do UX designers do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role has different meanings to different people. I really like this &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-skills/&quot;&gt;list of UX designer skills&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you need to be an expert in all of those things. But, if you are good at a few (and have an appreciation for why the rest are important) then I think you’ll make a good UX designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-days&quot;&gt;Open days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, but would like to know more, we have 2 open days coming up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newport on Tuesday 1 November from 2pm to 7pm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Titchfield on Thursday 3 November from 2pm to 7pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/aboutus/contactus/officelocations&quot;&gt;View map and contact details on ONS website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-it-like-at-ons&quot;&gt;What’s it like at ONS?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing that convinced me to work at ONS was this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/product-is-a-team-sport-c50d234745e#.uk86uylv5&quot;&gt;Product is a team sport, a talk/blog post by Matt Jukes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get an insight into the culture here at ONS, then I recommend that you take 10 minutes to read that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the working culture and good pay (£35k) there are some great benefits, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flexible working&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a Civil Service pension&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an on-site nursery at our Newport site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an on-site gym&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;free car-parking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a training/conference budget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 3 young kids and I commute from Swansea to Newport each day (50 miles each way). I don’t think I could do this job if it wasn’t for the (actually) flexible working arrangements and support from my managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apply&quot;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closing date for applications is Tuesday 15 November 2016. If you have any questions, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton&quot;&gt;direct message (DM) me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. My DMs are open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-to-full-job-descriptions&quot;&gt;Links to full job descriptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512692&quot;&gt;User experience (UX) designer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512654&quot;&gt;User researcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 02:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/work-with-me-at-office-for-national-statistics-ons/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/work-with-me-at-office-for-national-statistics-ons/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ons</category>
        
        <category>hiring</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a digital delivery culture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenHolliday/status/657085783250227200&quot;&gt;digital delivery culture poster&lt;/a&gt;, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenHolliday&quot;&gt;Ben Holliday&lt;/a&gt; and his team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DWPDigital&quot;&gt;DWP Digital&lt;/a&gt; (Department for Work and Pensions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Digital delivery culture &amp;gt; How we need to work to make this happen. Starting the conversation… / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DigitalDWP&quot;&gt;@DigitalDWP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SJpxh0RiFj&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/SJpxh0RiFj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ben Holliday (@BenHolliday) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenHolliday/status/657085783250227200&quot;&gt;October 22, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you can’t access the tweet, here are the points from the poster:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work in the open&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share, not send&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right people, same room&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less process, more progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t wait for permission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show the thing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People, not resources&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build strong communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fail fast and learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-thoughts&quot;&gt;My thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to look back over design principles like these every now and then. They help me to focus on what’s important. Creating a good culture is really hard, but it’s essential if you need individuals to work together as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 21:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/creating-a-digital-delivery-culture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/creating-a-digital-delivery-culture/</guid>
        
        
        <category>digital</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>poster</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visual note-taking  with Eleanor Beer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My notes from the Visual Notetaking Made Easy event on Thursday 11th August at Innovation House, Magor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/sketchnote-elements.png&quot; alt=&quot;A drawing of a star and some lines from my sketchbook.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual note-taking is basically notes with doodles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s also known as sketchnoting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The basic processes is; listen, filter, draw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s useful for creating user journeys, meeting facilitation and conference recording&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listening is a key skill!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improves memory recall&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Captures emotion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s fun!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who are usually quiet in meetings feel included&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can help people with low literacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elements&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basics: layout, words, objects, containers, lines and arrows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pictographs are drawings of things; like a book, dog, mobile phone or aeroplane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ideographs are pictures that represent an idea; like balance, collaboration, education or digital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People (stick figures and smiley faces)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layouts: linear, circular, random, path or grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shopping-list&quot;&gt;Shopping list&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pens&quot;&gt;Pens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tigerpens.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Tiger Pens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penandpaper.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Pen &amp;amp; Paper, Cardiff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rohdesign.com/handbook&quot;&gt;The Sketchnote Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.danroam.com/the-back-of-the-napkin/&quot;&gt;The Back of the Napkin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sketchnotesbook.com/&quot;&gt;Sketchnotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://payhip.com/b/uvS3&quot;&gt;A Pocket Guide to Sketchnoting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;follow-eleanor-beer&quot;&gt;Follow Eleanor Beer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eleanorbeer.com/&quot;&gt;www.eleanorbeer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eleanorbeer&quot;&gt;Eleanor on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/eleanorbeer/&quot;&gt;Eleanor on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 14:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/visual-note-taking-workshop-with-eleanor-beer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/visual-note-taking-workshop-with-eleanor-beer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
        <category>talk</category>
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things my little girls have taught me about feminism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A rough transcript of my talk on feminism at Ignite Swansea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/my-little-girls.png&quot; alt=&quot;My 2 little girls, smiling in a phone box.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my 2 little girls. Don’t be taken in by their cuteness, they are quite evil. Their favourite things are having meltdowns in the supermarket and making fun of my receding hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to start off with the definition of feminism. According to Google, feminism is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“the advocacy of women’s rights on the ground of the equality of the sexes”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me it’s about wanting to live in a equal society, and I just don’t think we are there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, gendered listening starts at the age of four. My eldest is 5. She’s had one year of listening to adults talk about men and women in different ways, usually to the detriment of women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example of this: once when I was crossing the road I told her to wait for the green man. She asked “why is it always a man?”. This really hit home. It made me realise just how the world is weighted in favour of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My girls love Disney Princesses. Initially I was worried that these were too girly, too clichéd. Are they good role models for my kids? But I quickly learnt why they love them. They are exciting, strong, positive role models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So together, we’re exploring different films and characters. Like My Little Pony: Equestrian Girls. This is an alternative universe where the ponies are human girls who form a rock band, have magical powers and work together to defeat evil dragons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They enjoy “boy stuff” too, like Marvel and Transformers. But it feels very segregated still. Boys toys and girls toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think companies like Disney and Marvel are slowly creating more diverse role models for kids to look up to though. Apparently, the next Iron Man film will star a 15-year-old black girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Star Wars is another good example of franchise that’s being updated. Princess Leia is pretty strong characted in the early films, but in one of them she’s tied up as Jabba’s sex slave, so I’m not going to watch that with my kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the new star wars, Leia is a General. And one of the lead characters, Rey, is 😮 a woman! I can’t wait to watch these films with my kids when they’re a bit older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new Star Wars film coming out too. It’s called Rogue One, and it also stars 😱 a woman! Apparently this is a genuine YouTube comment about the trailer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’m not sexist but Star Wars is about men, men fighting to save the universe. If women can do the same as men, what’s the point? I won’t be seeing this. If you need me I’ll be watching anime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a typical example of the way men react online when gender roles are reversed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trolls have been out in force over the new Ghostbusters film too. But look how happy these 2 girls are. This is what representation in the media can do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/ghostbusters-representation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kristen Wiig meeting 2 girls dressed in Ghostbusters fancy dress.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The olympics have been full of men saying embarrassing things too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such as John Inverdale, saying that Andy Murray was “the first person ever to win two Olympic tennis gold medals”, completely forgetting that Venus and Serena Williams have won four each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/beggie_smalls/status/762545510930677760&quot;&gt;bloke on Twitter, mansplaining to olympic athlete&lt;/a&gt; Annemiek van Vleuten after her horrendous crash by saying: “the first lesson in bicycling, keep your bike steady… whether fast or slow”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly as bad as mansplaining is manspreading. Guys have a look down at your legs now and if you’re manspreading then do the people either side of you a favour and close them up a little. You’re not that big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/manspreading.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man on a train sitting with his legs very far apart.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit: WNYC New York Public Radio (CC BY-NC 2.0)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if like me, you’re keen to be a better man then I recommend following &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/manwhohasitall&quot;&gt;@manwhohasitall on twitter&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an account that takes headlines from trashy women’s magazines then aims them at men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Men! Is having it all really possible? Kids, relationship, beach hair, imaginative picnic ideas AND a PH balanced intimate area?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It highlights the absurd way that women are treated by the media sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m hear today as a sign of solidarity to say: “My name is Benjy and I’m a feminist”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and guys, it’s okay if you want to watch pink, sparkly things sometimes. It doesn’t mean you’re any less of a man. It doesn’t mean you’re gay. It doesn’t mean anything. Unless you want it to. Just relax and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/glitter-force.gif&quot; alt=&quot;A pink super hero draws a huge heart in the sky.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;update&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably look back on this and cringe. Being a feminist is hard and I’ve probably revealed some of inner prejudices here without realising it. If you have any feedback, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton&quot;&gt;let me know over on twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 12:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/things-my-little-girls-have-taught-me-about-feminism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/things-my-little-girls-have-taught-me-about-feminism/</guid>
        
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
        <category>talk</category>
        
        <category>family</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User experience (UX) designer skills</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A list of skills needed to be a user experience designer, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://centercentre.com/&quot;&gt;Centre Centre&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uxward/status/763797497307246592/photo/1&quot;&gt;Brandon Ward shared this list on twitter&lt;/a&gt;. It was shared as an image so I decided to write it up as text here for prosperity.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technical-skills&quot;&gt;Technical skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front-end development&lt;/strong&gt;: coding valid HTML, CSS, JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual design&lt;/strong&gt;: understanding the use of colour, grid, layout and typography&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile integration&lt;/strong&gt;: creating consistent experiences through responsive layouts, touch interactions and input techniques&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project management&lt;/strong&gt;: incorporating iterative design, agile practices and software development life cycles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information architecture&lt;/strong&gt;: planning experiences through site mapping, modelling and wireframes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interaction design&lt;/strong&gt;: building flow, form design, micro-interactions and transition animations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copywriting and content strategy&lt;/strong&gt;: writing microcopy, content modelling and content inventories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User research&lt;/strong&gt;: conducting field research, usability studies,  research synthesis and data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;soft-skills&quot;&gt;Soft skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenting&lt;/strong&gt;: sharing thoughts an design concepts with peers and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facilitating&lt;/strong&gt;: extracting design requirements and project direction from peers and stakeholders, while prompting a shared understanding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critiquing&lt;/strong&gt;: receiving, giving and training peers and stakeholders with constructive feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storytelling&lt;/strong&gt;: communicating and affirming to peers and stakeholders how decisions were made, how principles were arrived at, and how the design will improve the lives of the users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sketching&lt;/strong&gt;: communicating emerging ideas quickly and exploring problem space with peers and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leadership&lt;/strong&gt;: providing vision, direction and passion to peers and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 17:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-skills/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-skills/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
