<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjy Stanton</title>
    <description>Interaction Designer. Family Man. Music Snob.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 08:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 miles to Glasto</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/9-miles-to-glasto/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/9-miles-to-glasto/</guid>
        
        
        <category>images</category>
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>October 2018 bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;list-pairs&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@timberners_lee/one-small-step-for-the-web-87f92217d085&quot;&gt;One Small Step for the Web…&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I’ve always believed the web is for everyone. That’s why I and others fight fiercely to protect it. The changes we’ve managed to bring have created a better and more connected world.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwpdigital.blog.gov.uk/2018/10/02/why-re-use-is-the-best-design-because-civil-servants-are-users-too/&quot;&gt;Why re-use is the best design (because civil servants are users too)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;In government, we have access to lots of research and design patterns that have been tried and tested. If someone else has already solved a problem, we can reuse their design. This saves time and money and creates a consistent experience for the user.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://seeingdata.org/&quot;&gt;Seeing Data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Seeing Data is a group of research projects which aim to understand the place of data visualisations (like those in the examples below) in society. This website includes information about projects which have been completed, are currently underway, or are about to start.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://theblog.adobe.com/kevin-hoffman-designing-better-meetings/&quot;&gt;Productivity to the Max: Kevin Hoffman on Designing Better Meetings&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Information architect and design strategist Kevin Hoffman is passionate about improving meetings. It led him to write his first book, “Meeting Design,” in which he explains that meetings don’t have to be “painfully inefficient snoozefests” and suggests treating them as a design problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://userresearch.blog.gov.uk/2016/01/29/fillet-your-findings/&quot;&gt;Fillet your findings&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;In The Old Man and the Sea, Ernest Hemingway tells this story.  One day, Santiago goes out to sea, much further than other fisherman go. He engages in a herculean struggle to catch an enormous marlin. He thrashes all day and all night. The fight nearly kills him.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiyoung.com/diagram-generator/&quot;&gt;Diagram generator&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I’ve released the software to generate a mental model diagram. You can feed your spreadsheet to it and a mental model diagram (the top half of an opportunity map) will appear on the page.  The software expects your data to be in a certain format.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://uxdesign.cc/building-a-service-design-team-from-scratch-152d9c0701c&quot;&gt;Building a service design team from scratch&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I was recently asked by a client what they should consider when they were thinking about building a service design team from scratch. It made me think about how we went about building out our service design team from scratch.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sarawb.com/2015/09/10/everybody-hurts-content-for-kindness/&quot;&gt;Everybody Hurts: Content for Kindness&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Last month, I gave the most difficult talk I’ve ever given. It’s about something I’ve been thinking a lot about recently: making our content and design work for people who don’t fit our narrow perception of “normal.” Here’s the description:&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jessica.neely/digital-accessibility-course-week-one-a266e29e258b&quot;&gt;Digital Accessibility course — week one&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Last week I began a five week FutureLearn course to up my accessibility knowledge.  User experience refers to any experience of a user that is related to that technology.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://aycl.uie.com/virtual_seminars/creating_a_design_facilitation_practice&quot;&gt;Creating a Design Facilitation Practice&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;A disorganized or inefficient meeting is a workplace pain. At best, it’s a waste of time, and at worst, it creates new problems. Luckily, there’s a solution: creating a facilitation process to transform your meetings into what they should have been all along.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://public.digital/2018/10/12/internet-era-ways-of-working/&quot;&gt;Internet-era ways of working&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;An earlier draft of this list, stuck to the PD office door Our definition of digital says: “Applying the culture, processes, business models &amp;amp; technologies of the internet-era to respond to people’s raised expectations.” Once they’ve heard that, the next thing people always ask us is: “OK.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalblog.coop.co.uk/2017/02/08/building-whats-useful-governance-and-agile-delivery/&quot;&gt;Building what’s useful: governance and agile delivery&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I’ve had lots of conversations with colleagues in the Co-op about working in agile ways.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://orgdesignfordesignorgs.com/2018/10/16/the-most-important-role-in-your-design-org-team-lead/&quot;&gt;The Most Important Role In Your Design Org: Team Lead&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Discussions of design leadership tend to look upward, toward the executives and directors who sit atop the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-typography-can-save-your-life&quot;&gt;How Typography Can Save Your Life — ProPublica&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;After decades of silently shouting at the top of its lungs, the National Weather Service recently announced that it’s going to stop publishing its forecasts and weather warnings in ALL CAPS. Beginning May 11, for the first time ever, we’ll start seeing mixed-case letters.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://adamsilver.io/articles/designing-inclusively/&quot;&gt;Designing inclusively&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;First sent to my private mailing list.  Whilst the web is still young, it’s been around long enough for us to know about its power and its constraints. We know what these constraints are now because we’ve bent them so much over the years.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/how-much-documentation-to-include-in-a-style-guide/&quot;&gt;How much documentation to include in a style guide?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;It’s a question I often hear from the design systems teams I work with. The short answer is: include as much or as little documentation as needed. The longer answer is: it depends. Alright, now I’ll quit messing around and explain a bit more.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://lisacharlotterost.github.io/datavistools-revisited&quot;&gt;One Chart, Nine Tools – Revisited&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Tableau Public What can I say - Tableau Public works well for data like this. The embedded graphic is too massive to actually use it in an article, but it’s one of my favorite tool for exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@paulmsmith/design-systems-the-means-not-the-end-fc840c21b51e&quot;&gt;Design Systems — the means, not the end&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;When I bought my first house, it was a busy time, I just needed to get stuff done and quickly! Not unlike the teams a lot of us now work with.  They looked good in the store, I’d check the material, open and close the doors, etc and then I’d load up the car and be on my way home.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://mhclgdigital.blog.gov.uk/2018/10/25/data-and-information/&quot;&gt;It can be difficult to make data from information&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;The Digital Land services team recently ran a discovery in which we researched the barriers our users encounter when trying to find and use housing data. This is the first in a series of posts about those barriers, or what people sometimes call ‘friction’.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/designing-accessible-content-typography-font-styling-and-structure--cms-31934&quot;&gt;Designing Accessible Content: Typography, Font Styling, and Structure&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Creating and designing accessible content means more than just choosing accessible typography. Even with “perfect” font families in place on your website, people with low vision, cognitive, language, and learning disabilities may still struggle to process the text. &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myddelton.co.uk/blog/user-research-is-a-team-sport&quot;&gt;User research is a team sport&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;‘User research is a team sport’ is the most powerful thing I’ve learned in government. Forget user needs. Forget discovery, alpha, beta, live. Forget agile. Forget the service standard and service assessments. This is the one thing I would save in a fire.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwpdigital.blog.gov.uk/2018/10/29/what-i-learned-as-an-interaction-designer-at-datajam-north-east/&quot;&gt;What I learned as an interaction designer at DataJam North East&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;The event aimed to bring the data and service design communities closer together and help solve problems affecting the North East region by holding both a hack (an intensive collaboration on a data or software project) and a free-form discussion called an unconference as part of the same event.&lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/october-2018-bookmarks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/october-2018-bookmarks/</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>September 2018 bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;list-pairs&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethanmarcotte.com/wrote/accessibility-is-not-a-feature/&quot;&gt;Accessibility is not a feature. — ethanmarcotte.com&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I care pretty deeply about accessible design. I wouldn’t call myself an accessibility specialist, mind you, but I’ve always felt that “designing for the web” means ensuring our work is accessible as broadly as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog-louisedowne-com.cdn.ampproject.org/c/s/blog.louisedowne.com/2018/04/03/why-its-never-a-good-time-for-service-design/amp/&quot;&gt;Why it’s never a good time for service design&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Picture the scene: you’ve just joined a new team, they’re doing good work but they’re plugging away at the wrong problem.  You bide your time, thinking of ways to bring them round.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://uxplanet.org/from-idea-to-appstore-a-design-sprint-case-study-a7781093de8d&quot;&gt;From Idea to App Store: A Design Sprint Case Study&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;If you’ve ever worked on an app, you can only dream of that feeling of pure joy when you open the App Store and see your app featured on the homepage.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://alistapart.com/article/the-core-model-designing-inside-out-for-better-results&quot;&gt;The Core Model: Designing Inside Out for Better Results&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;If you’ve worked on a website design with a large team or client, chances are good you’ve spent some time debating (arguing?) with each other about what the homepage should look like, or which department gets to be in the top-lev&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Ellayanor/team-charters-for-diverse-teams-a50add65dd92&quot;&gt;Team Charters for Diverse Teams&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Team Charters are things which come up a lot, and are often triggers for really insightful conversations about how teams work together and function well. A team charter is basically a set of principles for how a group of people work as a team, that a team draft together and agree to abide by.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamiearnold.com/blog/2014/07/22/seven-questions-to-build-a-roadmap&quot;&gt;Seven questions to build a roadmap&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;In my last post I wrote about why roadmaps are for everyone. This post is about techniques for building one and how the use of language can help align your pure agile or mixed methodology programmes.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cassierobinson/a-user-manual-for-me-d3a851fbc694&quot;&gt;A user manual for me&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;There are lots of ways to build good teams and working relationships. But, before you get to the relational matter of teams, platforms and systems, it’s important for people to know your preferences as an individual.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2018/09/importance-manual-accessibility-testing/&quot;&gt;The Importance Of Manual Accessibility Testing&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Automated accessibility tests are a great resource to have, but they can’t automatically make your site accessible. Use them as one step of a larger testing process.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2018/09/27/assistive-technology-tools-you-can-use-at-no-cost/&quot;&gt;Assistive technology tools you can use at no cost&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;GDS’s Accessibility Empathy Lab is open to anyone from the public sector. Since we blogged about the lab, we’ve seen a huge increase in visitors coming in to use it as an assistive technology space.&lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/september-2018-links/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/september-2018-links/</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to focus in open plan offices</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;Earlier this week, I asked the Twitter hive mind for tips how to get focussed work done when working in open plan offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Designers who work in open plan offices — how do you make space and time for focussed work?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Benjy Stanton (@benjystanton) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton/status/1044599479721218048?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 25, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got some great responses (thanks everyone!) so I’ve captured them here for prosperity…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;put-on-some-headphones&quot;&gt;Put on some headphones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get some headphones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The bigger the better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noise cancelling ones are good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listen to white noise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or don’t listen to anything – just wear them to discourage people from interrupting you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work-from-home&quot;&gt;Work from home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That’s it really, just work from home more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;manage-your-calendar&quot;&gt;Manage your calendar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block out slots in your calendar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decline non-essential meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan to do focussed work when you’re at your most productive – for me that’s early in the morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-using-distracting-apps&quot;&gt;Stop using distracting apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put do not disturb on Slack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn your emails off&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;http://heyfocus.com/&quot;&gt;Focus app&lt;/a&gt; to help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-away-from-your-desk&quot;&gt;Get away from your desk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Book yourself a meeting room&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Skype pods and breakout spaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hide in usability labs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find anywhere that’s quiet or tucked away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-anti-social&quot;&gt;Be anti-social&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scowl at people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put a hoodie on&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put up ‘do not disturb’ signs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure people know you’re busy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;look-after-yourself&quot;&gt;Look after yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working in distracting environments can be stressful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t ignore the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-focus-in-open-plan-offices/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-focus-in-open-plan-offices/</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A plan for accessible charts</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;A list of user research findings, accessibility report findings, best practice, resources and good ideas that I’ve collected over the past 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to create some prototype charts and start iterating. But I wanted to write-up and share the work so far, in case it’s useful to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;colour&quot;&gt;Colour&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check colour meets contrast standards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t use colour alone to convey meaning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider colour blind users (use colour blind simulators to check)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charts should be readable in black and white&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check design works in high contrast mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;line-and-bar-style&quot;&gt;Line and bar style&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider using patterns or textures to distinguish bars and lines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/GL/low-vision-a11y-tf/wiki/Informational_Graphic_Contrast_(Minimum)&quot;&gt;Increase minimum size of elements in chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Label the data directly (instead of a separate keys or legend)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;present-data-in-alternative-ways&quot;&gt;Present data in alternative ways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use titles and descriptions to support the chart&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/government-digital-strategy/government-digital-strategy#people-who-are-already-online&quot;&gt;Allow users to view data in an html table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow users to download the data as a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interactive-elements&quot;&gt;Interactive elements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interactive elements must have affordance (for example, links should be blue with an underline)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure interactive elements are usable without a mouse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All interactive elements should have a focus style&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tool tips can help some users to read charts, especially users with cognitive conditions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download links labels must include file format and size&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Headings, links and button text must be unique and descriptive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If an experience cannot be made accessible, create another route for users to get that information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;typography&quot;&gt;Typography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a minimum font size&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use consistent font and spacing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lines are less than 80 characters wide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid italics and block capitals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a san-serif font with thick letters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure text can be resized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test the content doesn’t overflow or become truncated when font size is increased&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nest headings in order (for example, H2s only appear after H1s)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t skip heading levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;layout&quot;&gt;Layout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design with a mobile-first mindset&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a consistent design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use simple, well known chart types that users are more likely to understand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a limited number of reusable templates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strive to use a simple design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading and navigation order is logical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;svgs&quot;&gt;SVGs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use SVG because they are scalable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users can zoom in and they won’t become pixellated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structure the SVG carefully, so that it makes use of their accessible powers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use ARIA tags to improve accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/tips-accessible-svg/&quot;&gt;Tips for Creating Accessible SVG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://decks.tink.uk/2017/lws/index.html#cover&quot;&gt;Making SVG accessible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tink.uk/accessible-svg-line-graphs/&quot;&gt;Accessible SVG line graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/how-to-make-charts-with-svg/&quot;&gt;How to Make Charts with SVG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;html-mark-up&quot;&gt;HTML mark-up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; element to wrap the chart&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figcaption&lt;/code&gt; for the chart title&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;footer&lt;/code&gt; inside the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; element to contain any notes or citation information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-resources&quot;&gt;Other resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://accessibility.psu.edu/images/charts/&quot;&gt;Charts &amp;amp; Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ontario.ca/document/ontario-design-guide/charts&quot;&gt;Charts, graphs and infographics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://colorbrewer2.org/#type=sequential&amp;amp;scheme=BuGn&amp;amp;n=3&quot;&gt;Color brewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.highcharts.com/a11y.html&quot;&gt;Highcharts accessibility demos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webaim.org/resources/contrastchecker/&quot;&gt;Color Contrast Checker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://colororacle.org/&quot;&gt;Color Oracle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://michelf.ca/projects/sim-daltonism/&quot;&gt;Sim Daltonism colour blindness simulator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://littlebigdetails.com/post/35775193711/trello-color-blind-friendly-mode-makes&quot;&gt;Trello - Color Blind Friendly Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://24ways.org/2012/colour-accessibility&quot;&gt;Colour Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@sidgtl/designing-for-colour-blindness-b74a9d012ef2&quot;&gt;Designing for Colour Blindness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;examples-of-charts-across-uk-government-services&quot;&gt;Examples of charts across UK government services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethnicity-facts-figures.service.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;Ethnicity facts and figures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gds.blog.gov.uk/2012/11/12/updating-performance-dashboard/&quot;&gt;Updating the GOV.UK Performance Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/performance&quot;&gt;GOV.UK Performance Dashboards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alphagov/magna-charta&quot;&gt;Magna Charta repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alphagov.github.io/magna-charta/&quot;&gt;Magna Charta demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-export-finance-annual-report-and-accounts-published&quot;&gt;UK Export Finance: annual report and accounts published&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/a-plan-for-accessible-charts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/a-plan-for-accessible-charts/</guid>
        
        
        <category>accessibility</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to lead user-centred design</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;My brief notes from the Government Digital Service (GDS) essentials of leadership training, run by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rebeccakemp&quot;&gt;Rebecca Kemp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Adewunmi&quot;&gt;Ade Adewunmi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tell-a-good-story&quot;&gt;Tell a good story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how to talk about what you and your team do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how to talk to people who aren’t familiar with user-centred design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help your team to talk about it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you can talk about your profession, and the product you are working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-common-ground&quot;&gt;Find common ground&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everybody cares about user-centred design, so don’t be a purist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You only have to convince people enough to let you do your job, you don’t have to convert them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acknowledge other peoples’ expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work to find common ground, almost everyone wants to improve the service they’re working on in some way. Learn how to talk about things in a way that they can relate to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be pragmatic. What concrete steps can you take to improve the service? Making everything better for everyone at the same time is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how much things cost, and show people what savings can be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;look-after-your-team-and-yourself&quot;&gt;Look after your team (and yourself)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protect your team from things that can disrupt their flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make decisions for them (when they need you to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading can be exhausting. It requires a lot of emotional labour. Find things that you can do to recharge. Plan at least one of these things into your schedule every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t let yourself burn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speak to friends and mentors outside of your organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-lead-user-centred-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-lead-user-centred-design/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>August 2018 bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;list-pairs&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/colorguide/index.html&quot;&gt;Your Friendly Guide to Colors in Data Visualisation&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Once upon a time, I tweeted on an urgent matter. “Can somebody tell me how to get better with color?” I wrote.&quot; My color decisions are awful.&quot; I got a lot of replies with links to tools. They were awesome, so I collected them in a blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2DLK3qK2aw0&quot;&gt;Blocked from benefits ... literally&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Jaki has been living without disability benefits for almost a year. When she applied for employment and support allowance, she had to attend a work capability assessment. After an hour's journey, she found she was not able to access the testing centre. Her experience is not unique.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethanmarcotte.com/wrote/accessibility-is-not-a-feature/&quot;&gt;Accessibility is not a feature. — ethanmarcotte.com&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I care pretty deeply about accessible design. I wouldn’t call myself an accessibility specialist, mind you, but I’ve always felt that “designing for the web” means ensuring our work is accessible as broadly as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/aug-2018-links/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/aug-2018-links/</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>July 2018 bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;list-pairs&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@avfletcher/design-backgrounds-are-over-rated-85ed59f7c7df&quot;&gt;Design backgrounds are over-rated&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;For strategic, systems and service design at least, design backgrounds are over-rated. If you insist on recruiting only “talent” with such backgrounds, you will dramatically reduce your chances of finding candidates with the skills required design and deliver change.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevehoneyman.co.uk/blog/blue-notes/&quot;&gt;Responsive Blue Note Album sleeves recreated in the browser using HTML and CSS&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Over the last few months I’ve been busying myself trying to re-create some of Reid Miles iconic album sleeves  in the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/gel/guidelines/how-to-make-accessible-animated-images&quot;&gt;How to make Accessible Animated Images&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Animated images can really enhance user experience and understanding, but there are limitations. If they’re not designed in an accessible way, GIFs can be distracting or could even cause seizures.  To make sure your animated images are safe and accessible for all, here’s what you need to know.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/cbc-digital-labs/planting-the-service-design-seeds-at-cbc-f0ced9a0f225&quot;&gt;Planting the Service Design Seeds at CBC&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Hi there ?, thanks for stopping by! My name is Hira and I’m excited to introduce the Service Design practice at CBC.  We define Service Design as a human-centred approach to creating and delivering holistic, seamless audience experiences across the CBC ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://civilservice.blog.gov.uk/2018/07/06/keeping-in-touch-helps-me-feel-like-me/&quot;&gt;Keeping in touch helps me feel like me&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;So, how have I used my time, what are the challenges you face as the mother of a young baby away from work, and how have I tackled them?  I’ve thought of myself as a member of two minority groups for quite some time - a woman and a member of the LGBT community.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visionofbritain.org.uk/data&quot;&gt;Data Access&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;The GB1900 project computerised all the place names and other text on the Second Edition County Series six-inch-to-one-mile maps covering the whole of Great Britain, published by the Ordnance Survey between 1888 and 1914 -- 1900 for short.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://larahogan.me/blog/leadership-style-colors/&quot;&gt;Leadership Style Colors&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Search for “leadership styles” on Google, and you’ll find lots of different articles describing the various types and numbers of leadership styles. Here are some examples of articles that say there are five, six, seven, eight, nine, and twelve leadership styles.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/standards-guidelines/wcag/new-in-21/&quot;&gt;What's New in WCAG 2.1&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;This page lists the new success criteria in Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1.  It includes quotes from personas (fictional people) to help you understand some aspects of the success criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2018/07/pattern-library-first-css/&quot;&gt;Pattern Library First: An Approach For Managing CSS&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Upgrade your inbox and get our editors’ picks twice a month.  CSS can be hard to manage across a project, especially when you need to include media queries for various breakpoints and fallbacks for older browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@karenyunqiuli/lifecycle-a-simple-service-design-mapping-technique-69bdec645ad6&quot;&gt;Lifecycle: a simple service design mapping technique&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Being a part of an in-house service design team in the BBC comes with a lot of perks. I get to work on many complex and exciting projects, with a wide range of stakeholders. Every project is an opportunity to explore something new.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@sanjaypoyzer/3-questions-everybody-should-know-the-answer-to-e6a91fe572b9&quot;&gt;3 questions everybody should know the answer to&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Whatever you’re working on, it probably needs to be delivered quickly.  There are always deadlines that need to be met, stakeholders who need to be managed, and meetings that need to be booked. In all the rush of the day-to-day, it’s often hard to work out what really needs to be achieved.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/guardian-masterclasses/2015/aug/07/data-visualisation-a-one-day-workshop-tobias-sturt-adam-frost-digital-course&quot;&gt;Data visualisation: A one-day workshop&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Learn how to transform data into beautiful infographics at this hands-on workshop with our data visualisation experts Adam Frost and Tobias SturtDates: Multiple dates availableTimes: Full-day course, 10am-4pm                Whether you’re working on a presentation, a website or teaching materia&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://contentdesign.london/usability/readability-guidelines/&quot;&gt;Readability guidelines&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Not brand or tone of voice just the mechanics of the language that are usually in style guides. So how to write a date or numerals vs numbers.   But the term ‘style guide’ seems to mean different things to different people.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mariecheung/outcome-based-service-mapping-feec7e1937da&quot;&gt;Outcome-based service mapping&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;At the Department for Work and Pensions in the UK government, I work with many teams who are currently tasked with replacing internal systems and improving the staff experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/process/flexbox-layout/&quot;&gt;Making Data Viz Without SVG Using D3 &amp;amp; Flexbox&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Bye bye tricky alignments.  A few months ago, my co-worker Matt and I were collaborating on a project. I had been building a stacked bar chart in D3.js, and was seriously struggling to get the bars to stack on top of each other nicely and to animate from the bottom of the graphic instead of the top.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://larahogan.me/blog/feedback-equation/&quot;&gt;Feedback Equation&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;As I mention in my book Demystifying Public Speaking, humans are mostly bad at giving feedback. We’re also really bad at preparing ourselves to receive feedback.  Many of us are paralyzed by the fear of having these awkward conversations.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://tom.loosemore.com/2018/07/17/interview-in-offscreen-magazine/&quot;&gt;Interview in Offscreen Magazine&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Last year I was interviewed by the mercurial Kai Brach for his magazine Offscreen, which seeks to highlight the human side of technology, and does so in style. You should subscribe.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://alistapart.com/article/webmentions-enabling-better-communication-on-the-internet&quot;&gt;Webmentions: Enabling Better Communication on the Internet&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Over 1 million Webmentions will have been sent across the internet since the specification was made a full Recommendation by the W3C—the standards body that guides the direction of the web—in early January 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/bbc-news-labs/beyond-800-words-prototyping-new-story-formats-for-news-e3102e783b5f&quot;&gt;Beyond 800 words: prototyping new story formats for news&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;News on the internet is largely served up as 500 to 800-word articles — a legacy of newspapers. Although the digital article has been enhanced and improved with new technologies, it still works on the assumption that ‘one size fits all’.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sarasoueidan.com/blog/toggle-switch-design/&quot;&gt;Sara Soueidan – Freelance front-end Web developer, author &amp;amp; speaker&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Yesterday I was working on creating the slides and accompanying demos for my upcoming Web Directions Code talk next week. One of the demos I’m creating is a basic proof of concept for a simple switch that is used to switch the theme of a UI from light to dark and vice versa.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://alphagov.github.io/wcag-primer/#wcag-2-0-getting-started&quot;&gt;WCAG 2.0 Primer alpha&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;This document will help you get up to speed with WCAG 2.0 quickly and avoid common mistakes people make when creating or updating web content. You will find this really helpful if you design, build or create web content.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.marvelapp.com/body-text-small/&quot;&gt;Your Body Text Is Too Small&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Body text is the key component in communicating the main bulk of a message or story, and it’s probably the most important element on a website, even if people sometimes read just the headlines.&lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/july-2018-links/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/july-2018-links/</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>June 2018 bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;list-pairs&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://emilywebber.co.uk/a-decent-remote-show-and-tell-set-up/&quot;&gt;A decent remote show and tell set up&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Many organisations work with dispersed teams or stakeholders, so there must be an easy way to do an engaging remote show and tell, surely… right? I couldn’t find one, this is my ongoing request to find my own and my current set up.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://alistapart.com/article/cult-of-the-complex&quot;&gt;The Cult of the Complex&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;In an industry that extols innovation over customer satisfaction, and prefers algorithm to human judgement (forgetting that every algorithm has human bias in its DNA), perhaps it should not surprise us that toolchains have replaced know-how&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://inclusive-components.design/cards/&quot;&gt;Cards&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Some of the components I've explored here have specific standardized requirements in order to work as expected. Tab interfaces, for example, have a prescribed structure and a set of interaction behaviors as mandated by the WAI-ARIA specification.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG21/&quot;&gt;Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1 covers a wide range of recommendations for making Web content more accessible. Following these guidelines will make content more accessible to a wider range of people with disabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hodigital.blog.gov.uk/2018/06/07/creating-a-list-of-services/&quot;&gt;Creating a list of services&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;The Home Office is developing a list of services it delivers, or delivers a part of, as an end user might know them, or might search for them online. By end user, we mean citizens, visitors, people living here from abroad, employers, universities, airlines, port operators and many more.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.trello.com/how-design-teams-are-using-trello-ultimate-guide&quot;&gt;How Design Teams Are Using Trello: The Ultimate Round Up&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Design teams are arguably the most underrated, understaffed, but also one of the most important teams at your company.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Elijah_Meeks/making-annotations-first-class-citizens-in-data-visualization-21db6383d3fe&quot;&gt;Making Annotations First-Class Citizens in Data Visualization&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I’m convinced that annotations are where we’re going to see the next wave of innovation in data visualization.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mattedgar.com/2018/06/06/look-after-the-water-reflections-1-year-into-my-work-at-nhs-digital/&quot;&gt;“Look after the water” – reflections 1 year into my work at NHS Digital&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Other people’s jobs are endlessly fascinating. At a birthday celebration a couple of years ago I got talking to Johnny, a family friend who works as an aquarium curator. He told me a surprising thing about his work: how little of his time he spends actually looking after the fish.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.nytimes.com/reimagining-the-new-york-times-digital-story-experience-ff698541ac09&quot;&gt;Reimagining The New York Times Digital Story Experience&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;The New York Times publishes more than 150 articles a day to our iOS and Android apps, and our desktop and mobile websites. All of these platforms were originally developed by separate teams, so each had its own implementation and user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.designbetter.co/designops-handbook&quot;&gt;DesignOps Handbook&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;DesignOps is the key to scaling digital product design teams with more efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.louisedowne.com/2018/06/14/15-principles-of-good-service-design/&quot;&gt;15 principles of good service design&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;What is a good service and why are we so afraid to talk about it? I’ve been asking myself this question a lot recently.  In a bid to find out, I tweeted this a few weeks ago and – bar a couple of people also wondering the same thing – got pretty much tumbleweeds in return.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/service-manual/measuring-success/measuring-service-benefits&quot;&gt;Measuring the benefits of your service&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Building the wrong thing can be very costly. It wastes users’ time, causes frustration and leads to people getting in touch via less cost effective channels.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@loft27design/designers-as-power-brokers-403338d79361&quot;&gt;Designers as power brokers&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I put this flag up in work a couple of weeks ago. It caused a bit of a conversation and people had different interpretations of what it meant. I thought it best to explain the way I intended it.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://pds.blog.parliament.uk/2018/06/13/making-the-hours-count-not-counting-the-hours/&quot;&gt;Making the hours count, not counting the hours&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;I’ve been a content designer for about two years. I started just after my daughter was born. It’s taken some close supervision, support, and some pretty intense onboarding, but we’re both getting used to our roles.  We’re taking small steps because getting used to new things takes time.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://cm.engineering/how-to-test-accessibility-of-emails-b68fed03f5f4&quot;&gt;How to test accessibility of emails&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Testing for accessibility in your emails doesn’t have to be a chore. Making accessible and inclusive emails will increase your target audience (1, 2, 3) and will have other unintended benefits. These other benefits are known as the Curb-Cut effect. When people first introduced curb cuts (i.e.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://design-system.service.gov.uk&quot;&gt;Design your service using GOV.UK styles, components and patterns&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;GOV.UK uses cookies to make the site simpler. Find out more about cookies  Use this design system to make your service consistent with GOV.UK. Learn from the research and experience of other service teams and avoid repeating work that’s already been done.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/leading-service-design/service-mapping-and-different-types-of-maps-604a1a22e22c&quot;&gt;Service mapping and different types of maps&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Written by Ben Holliday. Based on work developed with Kirsty Sinclair and feedback from the FutureGov design team.  There’s a question of why designers make so many maps. We love maps.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@deanvipond/jelly-flood-the-world-of-design-seen-through-the-lens-of-a-kids-cartoon-f2d854bf4db9&quot;&gt;Jelly Flood! The world of design, seen through the lens of a kids’ cartoon&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Maybe it was the sleep deprivation that parenthood brought, but Ben &amp;amp; Holly’s Little Kingdom was one of my favourite TV shows whilst my children were younger. It was funny and smart, and had some wry comments about class and royalty.  These are the Fairies. They live in a castle, and can do magic.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/service-manual/agile-delivery/working-across-organisational-boundaries&quot;&gt;Working across organisational boundaries&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;You may need to work with other organisations or teams across your department to build services that make sense to users.  This is because separate teams are often responsible for different chunks of a full end-to-end journey like becoming a childminder or setting up a company.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;list-pairs__name&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/twitter-design-research/all-in-sync-how-our-designers-keep-up-with-the-latest-design-system-assets-98687925d7e&quot;&gt;All in Sync: How our designers keep up with the latest design system assets&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Design systems empower designers to focus on the many unique problems that they’re solving while providing a consistent experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/june-2018-links/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/june-2018-links/</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes – series 01 episode 06</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;Inflatable bowels, Twitter charts and busy, busy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sharing-charts-on-twitter-at-time-of-release&quot;&gt;Sharing charts on Twitter at time of release&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to remember back to Monday now, but one meeting in particular stood out. A few of us got together to try and improve the ‘sharing charts on Twitter at time of release’ workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the unique (it’s probably not unique) way ONS handles and publishes sensitive data, creating an image of chart in time for 9:30am publishing is really tricky and it’s causing headaches for a few of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tuesday&quot;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;show-and-tell-with-the-publishing-team&quot;&gt;Show and tell with the publishing team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I was asked to run a show and tell for the publishing team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The publishing team are the people who use the ONS website’s content management system to upload content so it can be published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminded me that we have made some progress in breaking down the silos in the department. But there is still more that can be done, and I’ve made a note to remind myself to spend more time observing the work that they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wednesday-was-intense&quot;&gt;Wednesday was intense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning I finished off my &lt;a href=&quot;https://dp-prototype-kit.netlify.com/sprint/25/geography-2/&quot;&gt;find data by location&lt;/a&gt; prototype, then presented it at our usual end-of-sprint show and tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SuepremeDesign&quot;&gt;Sue&lt;/a&gt; (graphic designer from Home Office Digital) visited. She spent some time chatting with the various design teams (thanks everyone who spent time showing her around). She has plans to start a cross-gov graphic design meet-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunch time, we walked around a giant inflatable bowel. Which was a completely normal thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;When you get invitied into an inflatable bowel you can’t say no 🤷‍♀️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mathew_weeks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@mathew_weeks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RachelPricetag?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@RachelPricetag&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NationJoseph?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@NationJoseph&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@benjystanton&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/cF4l3cgayx&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/cF4l3cgayx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Grace Elizabeth (@designergrace) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/designergrace/status/1004324407693709313?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst all this was going on we had our usual end-of-sprint ceremonies like retrospective and sprint planning. These are usually exhausting just by themselves. Especially for an introvert like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last of all, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SamHallWales&quot;&gt;Sam&lt;/a&gt; has rebooted the digital services monthly meeting. The team rarely get together, despite all sharing digital job roles, so it was good to be in the same room sharing news and updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thursday-was-also-intense&quot;&gt;Thursday was also intense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back — I had too much on on Thursday. My day went a bit like this…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 stand-ups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Usability testing with the publishing team part 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow-up chat about social media workflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meeting to discuss UX (user experience) designer progression pathways&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design community of practice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Usability testing with the publishing team part 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meeting to finish off sprint planning because we didn’t finish everything on Wednesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My head was spinning by the end of the day. Part of me feels proud that I can play an active role in 9 different meetings/discussions and still do some good work. Another part of me was just glad I had booked off Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day off with the kids — whoop!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/weeknotes-series-01-episode-06/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/weeknotes-series-01-episode-06/</guid>
        
        
        <category>weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
