<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjy Stanton</title>
    <description>Interaction Designer. Family Man. Music Snob.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 21:36:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Five things Andy taught me</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;This is my response to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mr_dudders&quot;&gt;Andy&lt;/a&gt;’s blog post &lt;a href=&quot;http://mrdudders.posthaven.com/five-things-benjy-taught-me&quot;&gt;five things Benjy taught me&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re tired by our cheesy web bromance, turn away now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy is a great leader. Over the past 2 years, he has gone out of his way to help me do a good job. And he’s used his experience and contacts to help me become a better designer. I honestly would not have survived my first 2 years as a civil servant without his help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 things he helped me to understand…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love the Web&lt;/strong&gt; — Andy loves the Web more than anyone I know. He’s shown me its value as a tool for empowering democracy and debate. And that the mission to publish open data is worth fighting for (because it will save the world).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work in the open&lt;/strong&gt; — to live and breath the web, you have to work in the open too. Blog, tweet, week note, speak at meet-ups. It helps you to formulate your ideas and become a better practitioner. It helps other teams going through the same problem. And it invites external people to advise you on the problems you are facing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support culture&lt;/strong&gt; — you have to work hard at culture. Doing digital work in big organisations that don’t always understand its value is hard. Culture and supportive teams make it possible, but it doesn’t happen by accident. And it doesn’t happen from the top down.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust your team&lt;/strong&gt; — Andy trusts his team completely. He hires good people and he gets out of their way. This is what I am trying to do with the designers that I work with. In fact, everything I have learnt about management and leadership I have learnt from Andy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be human&lt;/strong&gt; — Andy has never asked me to be anything but myself. It doesn’t matter to him that I’m introverted, or that I’m a bit scruffy, or that I need to leave early to get home for the kids. Just work hard and be nice to people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy is making great things happen at ONS (Office for National Statistics) and he never takes any of the credit. If you have a chance to work with him, I recommend you take it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/5-things-andy-taught-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/5-things-andy-taught-me/</guid>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A user manual for me</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;I’m joining a new team in Office for National Statistics (ONS), so it seemed like a good time to finally create &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cassierobinson/a-user-manual-for-me-d3a851fbc694&quot;&gt;a user manual for me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conditions-i-like-to-work-in&quot;&gt;Conditions I like to work in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to work in open, inclusive environments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to be embedded into multi-disciplinary agile teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I prefer structured meetings that allow everyone to voice their opinion and vote on the best way forward&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to be surrounded by good design (posters and journey maps on walls, stickers on laptops)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-timeshours-i-like-to-work&quot;&gt;The times/hours I like to work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I live in Swansea and commute to Newport, which means I need to work an early shift in order to avoid the worst of the traffic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7am to 3pm are the hours I work most days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I work best in the mornings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-ways-to-communicate-with-me&quot;&gt;The best ways to communicate with me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m happy to use a mix of communication methods (face-to-face, email, Slack, Skype)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll get the best answers from me if I’ve got time to prepare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ways-i-like-to-receive-feedback&quot;&gt;The ways I like to receive feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I love demoing my work and presenting at show and tells&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need time to prepare for feedback sessions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I find over-the-shoulder comments difficult to process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-need&quot;&gt;Things I need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To regularly observe user research in person&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good digital tools like Trello, Slack and Google Drive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to have regular quiet days (no-meeting days and working-from-home days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-struggle-with&quot;&gt;Things I struggle with&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m an introvert, which means too many meetings can drain me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Long email threads with lots of contributors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acronyms and jargon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-love&quot;&gt;Things I love&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/government-design-principles&quot;&gt;Government design principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web standards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User-centred design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government Digital Service (GDS) service standard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogging and sharing my thoughts on Twitter (let me know if anything should be kept private)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-things-to-know-about-me&quot;&gt;Other things to know about me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have 3 young kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before ONS I worked at the Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency (DVLA) on the “Tell DVLA about a medical condition or disability” service as a user experience (UX) designer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I value &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.capwatkins.com/the-boring-designer&quot;&gt;boring design&lt;/a&gt; over creating shiny things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/a-user-manual-for-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/a-user-manual-for-me/</guid>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NaBloPoMo round-up</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;I did it! &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/category/nablopomo/&quot;&gt;30 posts in 30 days&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent more time tweaking the patterns and components on the blog, rather than writing actual articles, but I think that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heres-a-quick-highlight-reel&quot;&gt;Here’s a quick highlight reel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I created a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/category/images/&quot;&gt;new image post template&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/creating-the-image-post-layout/&quot;&gt;blogged about it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;a href=&quot;/feed.xml&quot;&gt;link to my RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; to the footer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/sids-words/&quot;&gt;list of words that my 2 year old says&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/interaction-design-tools/&quot;&gt;list of interaction design tools that I use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started adding some indieweb features to the site in the shape of &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/getting-started-with-indieweb/&quot;&gt;microformats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogged from my phone using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://workingcopyapp.com/&quot;&gt;Working Copy app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/nablopomo-progress/&quot;&gt;progress bar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/blog-stats/&quot;&gt;key figures dashboard&lt;/a&gt; for my blog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next and previous links to the bottom of articles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jukesie&quot;&gt;Jukesie&lt;/a&gt; for encouraging me to do it. And to Michelle for putting up with me blogging every night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/nablopomo-round-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/nablopomo-round-up/</guid>
        
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
        <category>release-notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learnt recently that definition lists (DLs) can have multiple definitions (DDs) for every term (DT) and I’m so here for it.</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/dl-lists/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/dl-lists/</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nice people saying nice things about the ONS website</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;It was great to see some smart people, that I really respect, recognising the good work that we’re doing in ONS (Office for National Statistics) digital publishing today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom’s original screenshot focused on a weirdly specific bit of something we did recently. But, even this small component went through some rigorous usability and A/B testing. It built upon a content pattern that already did a good job of meeting a clear user need (I need to know if I’m looking at the latest stuff).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is, there is lots more of this to come. This is just the tiniest bit of the work we’ve been doing over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I&amp;#39;ve congratulated &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mr_dudders?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@mr_dudders&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ONS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ONS&lt;/a&gt; for it separately -- and I will never stop. This is one of the biggest single improvements in a websites design ever. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/kXB4s75G1G&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/kXB4s75G1G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tom Forth (@thomasforth) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thomasforth/status/1067360583706652672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 27, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Quietly (too quietly!) the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ONS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ONS&lt;/a&gt; have been doing some exceptionally good work properly publishing their stats. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Dg7QNQdW8T&quot;&gt;https://t.co/Dg7QNQdW8T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tom Loosemore (@tomskitomski) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomskitomski/status/1067535685559701505?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 27, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Gotta love &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ONS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ONS&lt;/a&gt; Quietly getting the job done. 👏 👏 👏 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/qAGWKbeXar&quot;&gt;https://t.co/qAGWKbeXar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Steve Foreshew-Cain (@s_foreshew_cain) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/s_foreshew_cain/status/1067737646229872640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 28, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/nice-people-saying-nice-things-about-the-ons-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/nice-people-saying-nice-things-about-the-ons-website/</guid>
        
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>November 2018 bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@msjaneaustin/oh-god-help-us-not-another-thing-on-design-tasks-60fb3552ac55&quot;&gt;The hidden cost of design tasks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;It’s a strange thing, being diagnosed with a chronic disease. At first there’s just such relief, that this collection of horribleness has a name, and that its not ‘all in your mind’, or ‘stress’.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.nytimes.com/kickoff-kit-tools-to-help-teams-work-better-together-3ca6a06b4fc2&quot;&gt;Kickoff Kit: Tools to Help Teams Work Better Together&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;In order to build products successfully and quickly, your team has to work well together. But so often teams dive into projects without recognizing how each member best operates or what everyone is working towards.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://designnotes.blog.gov.uk/2018/11/05/how-we-document-components-and-patterns-in-the-gov-uk-design-system/&quot;&gt;How we document components and patterns in the GOV.UK Design System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;We’ve talked before about the GOV.UK Design System and how we’ve worked to make everything it contains accessible, easy to implement and of a high quality. But just as important as the design and code is the documentation that explains how to use it.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bigmedium.com/ideas/design-systems-mastering-design-at-scale-video.html&quot;&gt;Design Systems: Mastering Design at Scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Here’s a gift for you: years and years of experience building design systems, molded into a gorgeous video series. I teamed up with Brad Frost, Dan Mall and InVision to create Design Systems: Mastering Design at Scale, a set of videos to help you plan, build, use, and maintain design systems.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cushionapp.com/journal/improving-readability&quot;&gt;Improving Readability With Bigger Fonts and Higher Contrast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The title of this post should include a “duh”, but hear me out. A few weeks ago, something hit me—our fonts are too small. By accident, I hit cmd+plus in the browser, which bumped our fonts to 110%, and everything felt better.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/business-case/&quot;&gt;The Business Case for Digital Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;This article examines the rationale for organizations to address accessibility. It includes tangible and intangible benefits, and the risks of not addressing accessibility adequately. It explores how accessibility can:&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/ux-debt/&quot;&gt;UX Debt: How to Identify, Prioritize, and Resolve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Continually prioritizing fast and easy solutions may help us hit release dates in the short term, but over time, repeatedly choosing shortcuts will leave us with mounting experience issues that adversely impact our users.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalblog.ons.gov.uk/2018/11/14/product-people-west-south-product-for-apis-whats-the-difference/&quot;&gt;Product People West &amp;amp; South: Product for APIs, what’s the difference?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;As part of CMD (Customise my data) I was given the opportunity to choose which of out two teams I wanted to lead. I chose to focus on the APIs as this was the area I felt my knowledge was weakest.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@BenHolliday/prompts-for-design-leaders-working-with-product-teams-4345c5dea8df&quot;&gt;Prompts for design leaders working with product teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;When working with product teams, the job of a design leader is to make quick and accurate assessments about the focus and quality of the work being presented back to them. You should be able to answer the following questions.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digital-land.github.io/&quot;&gt;Digital Land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Prototype This is a prototype. Digital Land is a team at the Ministry of Housing, Communities &amp;amp; Local Government working to improve land and housing data for the emerging proptech sector.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iterate.org.uk/11-more-things-to-hate-about-hotels/&quot;&gt;11 more things to hate about hotels – iterate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;This week, I had to spend time in more than one hotel for work-related reasons. Whilst undergoing this trial, I read Sharon’s inspired post about UX anti-patterns in hotels.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nickcolley.co.uk/2018/11/16/accessibility-in-the-govuk-design-system.html&quot;&gt;Design System London: Accessibility in the GOV.UK Design System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;I’ve put together some of the tweets in a Twitter moment, if you’re into that. All the sources are linked from the speakers notes in the footnotes.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.nytimes.com/5-questions-with-giorgia-lupi-23e2ba972fd8&quot;&gt;5 Questions with Giorgia Lupi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;On October 18th, Giorgia Lupi, award-winning information designer, co-author of the book “Dear Data” and founder of Accurat, a data-driven design firm, stopped by the Times office to talk about her work and career.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@paulmsmith/white-label-wall-templates-1cdec749dae6&quot;&gt;White-label agile wall templates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;In “Agile walls what are they good for?” I wrote about the value of physical “agile walls”. However I often find a barrier to teams using them (and staying engaged with them) is the work needed to create and regularly update them.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalhealth.blog.gov.uk/2018/11/21/a-rota-for-retrospectives/&quot;&gt;A rota for retrospectives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;In agile teams, the ‘retrospective’ is an essential – maybe the most essential - meeting we have. At the end of every two week sprint, we get together for an hour to reflect on how the work got done so that we can learn from it.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollidazed.co.uk/2016/07/11/learning-to-enjoy-the-size-of-the-problem/&quot;&gt;Learning to enjoy the size of the problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Some thoughts about having fun at work.  Last week I had a good time speaking at a Glug event in Reading.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/standards-guidelines/atag/&quot;&gt;Authoring Tool Accessibility Guidelines (ATAG) Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;This page introduces the Authoring Tool Accessibility Guidelines (ATAG) web standard.  Authoring tools are software and services that “authors” (web developers, designers, writers, etc.) use to produce web content (static web pages, dynamic web applications, etc.).&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Ik_LHmZx8Y&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;Make Technology Work for Everyone: introducing digital accessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;This short animated film provides• A short introduction to digital accessibility,• Some reasons why digital inclusion is important,• 15 tips to help you start making your digital technology more accessible, usable, and inclusive.For more information, references and resources - including tools&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6YupsPD2gcU&quot;&gt;Voxxed Thessaloniki 2018 - Automated Visual Testing: The Missing Part of your CI Pipeline?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Voxxed Thessaloniki 2018 - Automated Visual Testing: The Missing Part of your CI Pipeline? by Viv Richards&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/loyal-to-the-network-redux-9df296cc69c6&quot;&gt;Loyal to the network [redux]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A few years ago now I read something by Emer Coleman that really struck a chord with me — this idea of being ’loyal to the network’ rather than to particular employers.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/public-innovators-network/what-if-boldness-were-an-explicit-value-of-the-civil-service-3df6a3d2d008&quot;&gt;What if boldness were an explicit value of the civil service?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot recently about what it takes to get difficult and meaningful things done. Why it’s hard, exhausting and incredibly rewarding to make progress.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/parliament-and-elections/devolution/local-boundaries-in-england-what-is-place/&quot;&gt;Local boundaries in England: What is ‘place’?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;In the last few years, a number of think-tanks have addressed the effects of Government policy on ‘place’. Concerns have centred around spatial variations in GDP across the UK, identifying public spending within a given area, and variations in productivity.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apgrimes.co.uk/2018/11/17/ux-is-negotiation/&quot;&gt;UX is negotiation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;If you were to say that someone was a good UX practitioner, you could mean a great many things. For example, you could be thinking of their ability to run a workshop, an interview or a testing session. You could be thinking of their prototyping, visual or interaction design skills.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/variable-fonts-wide-screen-layout/&quot;&gt;Variable Fonts and Wide-Screen Layouts: Adopting Data-Driven Progressive Enhancements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;We recently updated our website homepage, and, in addition to changing the content and visual design, we’ve incorporated two major technical changes: adding a new layout for users with wide screens, and using a variable font.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.memespring.co.uk/2015/09/14/product-land-part-3/&quot;&gt;Product Land (Part 3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;This is the 3rd and final part of an essay about design and possibilities.&lt;/dd&gt;
  
&lt;/dl&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/november-2018-bookmarks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/november-2018-bookmarks/</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog stats</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- You can't pass variables straight into includes, you have to capture them first https://jekyllrb.com/docs/includes/#passing-parameter-variables-to-includes  --&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;A quick post of blog stats that used to be on the homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-grid margin-top--s&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;flex-grid__col flex-grid__col--third&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;big-number&quot;&gt;
120
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;flex-grid__col flex-grid__col--third&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;big-number&quot;&gt;
21
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/category/&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;flex-grid__col flex-grid__col--third&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;big-number&quot;&gt;
36
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;pages&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-grid&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;flex-grid__col flex-grid__col--third&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;big-number&quot;&gt;
3
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/category/images&quot;&gt;images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;flex-grid__col flex-grid__col--third&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;big-number&quot;&gt;
4
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/category/notes&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/blog-stats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/blog-stats/</guid>
        
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The stickers on my laptop</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;Here are the descriptions for each of the stickers on my laptop lid right now. Descriptions go from top-left to bottom-right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Daliwch ati&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The welsh translation of “keep going”&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://international.gov-design.com/&quot;&gt;International design in government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A conference and community of designers working in government around the world&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Florence&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The content management system behind the ONS (Office for National Statistics) website&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://govdesign.tumblr.com/post/143158136883/download-the-sticker-be-bold-read-the-blog-post&quot;&gt;Be bold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/public-innovators-network/what-if-boldness-were-an-explicit-value-of-the-civil-service-3df6a3d2d008&quot;&gt;What if boldness were an explicit value of the civil service?&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JanetHughes&quot;&gt;Janet Hughes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Customise my data beta&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A mission patch for a project at ONS (Office for National Statistics), designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomten2two&quot;&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Smiley face&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A hand drawn smiley face on a blue dot sticker&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Order&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;From a set &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mr_dudders&quot;&gt;Andy&lt;/a&gt; brought in&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;One Team Gov&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oneteamgov.uk/&quot;&gt;One Team Gov&lt;/a&gt; logo&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Command&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A pixelated Apple keyboard command icon from &lt;a href=&quot;http://iconhandbook.co.uk/&quot;&gt;The Icon Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://govdesign.tumblr.com/post/147037699728/download-the-sticker-users-first&quot;&gt;Users First&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A classic GDS (Government Digital Service) motto&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Make data part of the web&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;One that I designed, based &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ldodds&quot;&gt;Leigh Dodds&lt;/a&gt;’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalblog.ons.gov.uk/2017/01/06/some-open-data-publishing-principles/&quot;&gt;open data publishing principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Better government by design #oneteamgov&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oneteamgov.uk/&quot;&gt;One Team Gov&lt;/a&gt; motto&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uxwales&quot;&gt;UX Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A UX (user experience) meet-up in Cardiff&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Change takes time&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://alysonfielding.com/2016/12/28/practical-action-stickers-doing/&quot;&gt;Practical Action&lt;/a&gt; set by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alysonf&quot;&gt;Alyson Fielding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Making data meaningful for everyone&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Carlie_Edge&quot;&gt;Carlie&lt;/a&gt; for the ONS (Office for National Statistics) digital content team&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Data discovery alpha&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A mission patch for a project at ONS (Office for National Statistics), designed by me&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;You are not the user&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marianthux/status/865180783996272640&quot;&gt;Marianthi Makra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Cake driven development&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dxw/status/542714402827689984&quot;&gt;a set from DXW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Build the right thing&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://pilot.works/&quot;&gt;Pilot Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;#OfTheGovernment&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A coveted shiny “hashtag of the government” – I think maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lauradee&quot;&gt;Laura&lt;/a&gt; saved this one for me?&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;ONS (Office for National Statistics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The ONS logo mark, which I’ve just realised has been put on the wrong way round – there goes my chance of getting head of design one day&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://govdesign.tumblr.com/post/143794301833/download-the-sticker-whats-the-user-need-white&quot;&gt;What is the user need?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Another classic GDS (Government Digital Service) sticker&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Go where the users are&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;I designed this one whilst I was working at Leadin – a Finnish service design agency that have now been bought out by &lt;a href=&quot;https://gofore.com/&quot;&gt;Gofore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Loyal to the network&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;I found this one in the sticker tub in work – based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/loyal-to-the-network-redux-9df296cc69c6&quot;&gt;a post by Jukesie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;ONS design team&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;One that the ONS (Office for National Statistics) design team designed and printed in-house&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Medical notifications and renewal service alpha&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A mission patch from the first service I worked on at DVLA (Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency)&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;/dl&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-stickers-on-my-laptop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/the-stickers-on-my-laptop/</guid>
        
        
        <category>images</category>
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I’ve added previous and next links, so users can skip to the posts published before and after this one.</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/adding-previous-and-next-links/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/adding-previous-and-next-links/</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
        <category>release-notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speaking at Service Design in Gov 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;Looks like me and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@kieran_forde&quot;&gt;Kieran&lt;/a&gt; will be speaking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://govservicedesign.net/2019/&quot;&gt;Service Design in Government 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference takes place in Edinburgh in March and we’ll be doing a case study on making stats easier to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bit about the talk from &lt;a href=&quot;https://govservicedesign.net/2019/sessions/index.php?session=102&quot;&gt;the conference website&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;at-this-session-you-will-learn-how-we&quot;&gt;At this session, you will learn how we:&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;worked with a multidisciplinary team across our department and the wider organisation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;gathered evidence to convince stakeholders of the need for simpler statistical reports&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;presented our work to senior stakeholders and regulatory bodies&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;learnt about the needs of end users and internal users&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;improved the service by co-designing and pair-writing with teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/speaking-at-service-design-in-gov-2019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/speaking-at-service-design-in-gov-2019/</guid>
        
        
        <category>nablopomo</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
