<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjy Stanton</title>
    <description>UX Designer. Family Man. Music Snob.</description>
    <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://benjystanton.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 01:32:11 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 01:32:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come and work with me at Office for National Statistics (ONS)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished my second week at ONS. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ons.digital/2016/10/21/my-first-week/&quot;&gt;read about my first week on the ONS Digital blog&lt;/a&gt;. My second week was spent kicking off a big new project, more about that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;were-hiring-designers-and-researchers&quot;&gt;We’re hiring designers and researchers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ONS are currently on the look out for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512692&quot;&gt;2 user experience (UX) designers&lt;/a&gt; and a few &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512654&quot;&gt;user researchers&lt;/a&gt;. The roles are based in either Newport or Titchfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-ux-designers-do&quot;&gt;What do UX designers do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role has different meanings to different people. I really like this &lt;a href=&quot;http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-skills/&quot;&gt;list of UX designer skills&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you need to be an expert in all of those things. But, if you are good at a few (and have an appreciation for why the rest are important) then I think you’ll make a good UX designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-days&quot;&gt;Open days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, but would like to know more, we have 2 open days coming up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newport on Tuesday 1 November from 2pm to 7pm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Titchfield on Thursday 3 November from 2pm to 7pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/aboutus/contactus/officelocations&quot;&gt;View map and contact details on ONS website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-it-like-at-ons&quot;&gt;What’s it like at ONS?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing that convinced me to work at ONS was this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://productforthepeople.xyz/product-is-a-team-sport-c50d234745e#.uk86uylv5&quot;&gt;Product is a team sport, a talk/blog post by Matt Jukes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get an insight into the culture here at ONS, then I recommend that you take 10 minutes to read that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the working culture and good pay (£35k) there are some great benefits, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flexible working&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a Civil Service pension&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an on-site nursery at our Newport site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an on-site gym&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;free car-parking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a training/conference budget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 3 young kids and I commute from Swansea to Newport each day (50 miles each way). I don’t think I could do this job if it wasn’t for the (actually) flexible working arrangements and support from my managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apply&quot;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closing date for applications is Tuesday 15 November 2016. If you have any questions, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton&quot;&gt;direct message (DM) me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. My DMs are open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-to-full-job-descriptions&quot;&gt;Links to full job descriptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512692&quot;&gt;User experience (UX) designer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/jobs.cgi?jcode=1512654&quot;&gt;User researcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 02:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/come-and-work-with-me-at-office-for-national-statistics-ons/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/come-and-work-with-me-at-office-for-national-statistics-ons/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ons</category>
        
        <category>hiring</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a digital delivery culture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenHolliday/status/657085783250227200&quot;&gt;digital delivery culture poster&lt;/a&gt;, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenHolliday&quot;&gt;Ben Holliday&lt;/a&gt; and his team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DWPDigital&quot;&gt;DWP Digital&lt;/a&gt; (Department for Work and Pensions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Digital delivery culture &amp;gt; How we need to work to make this happen. Starting the conversation… / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DigitalDWP&quot;&gt;@DigitalDWP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SJpxh0RiFj&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/SJpxh0RiFj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ben Holliday (@BenHolliday) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenHolliday/status/657085783250227200&quot;&gt;October 22, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you can’t access the tweet, here are the points from the poster:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work in the open&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share, not send&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right people, same room&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less process, more progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t wait for permission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show the thing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People, not resources&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build strong communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fail fast and learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-thoughts&quot;&gt;My thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to look back over design principles like these every now and then. They help me to focus on what’s important. Creating a good culture is really hard, but it’s essential if you need individuals to work together as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 21:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/creating-a-digital-delivery-culture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/creating-a-digital-delivery-culture/</guid>
        
        
        <category>digital</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>poster</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visual note-taking  with Eleanor Beer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My notes from the Visual Notetaking Made Easy event on Thursday 11th August at Innovation House, Magor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://benjystanton.github.io/assets/sketchnote-elements.png&quot; alt=&quot;A drawing of a star and some lines from my sketchbook.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual note-taking is basically notes with doodles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s also known as sketchnoting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The basic processes is; listen, filter, draw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s useful for creating user journeys, meeting facilitation and conference recording&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listening is a key skill!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improves memory recall&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Captures emotion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s fun!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who are usually quiet in meetings feel included&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can help people with low literacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elements&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basics: layout, words, objects, containers, lines and arrows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pictographs are drawings of things; like a book, dog, mobile phone or aeroplane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ideographs are pictures that represent an idea; like balance, collaboration, education or digital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People (stick figures and smiley faces)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layouts: linear, circular, random, path or grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shopping-list&quot;&gt;Shopping list&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pens&quot;&gt;Pens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tigerpens.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Tiger Pens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penandpaper.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Pen &amp;amp; Paper, Cardiff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rohdesign.com/handbook&quot;&gt;The Sketchnote Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.danroam.com/the-back-of-the-napkin/&quot;&gt;The Back of the Napkin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sketchnotesbook.com/&quot;&gt;Sketchnotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://payhip.com/b/uvS3&quot;&gt;A Pocket Guide to Sketchnoting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;follow-eleanor-beer&quot;&gt;Follow Eleanor Beer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eleanorbeer.com/&quot;&gt;www.eleanorbeer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eleanorbeer&quot;&gt;Eleanor on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/eleanorbeer/&quot;&gt;Eleanor on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 14:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/visual-note-taking-workshop-with-eleanor-beer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/visual-note-taking-workshop-with-eleanor-beer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
        <category>talk</category>
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things my little girls have taught me about feminism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A rough transcript of my talk on feminism at Ignite Swansea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://benjystanton.github.io/assets/my-little-girls.png&quot; alt=&quot;My 2 little girls, smiling in a phone box.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my 2 little girls. Don’t be taken in by their cuteness, they are quite evil. Their favourite things are having meltdowns in the supermarket and making fun of my receding hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to start off with the definition of feminism. According to Google, feminism is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“the advocacy of women’s rights on the ground of the equality of the sexes”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me it’s about wanting to live in a equal society, and I just don’t think we are there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, gendered listening starts at the age of four. My eldest is 5. She’s had one year of listening to adults talk about men and women in different ways, usually to the detriment of women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example of this: once when I was crossing the road I told her to wait for the green man. She asked “why is it always a man?”. This really hit home. It made me realise just how the world is weighted in favour of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My girls love Disney Princesses. Initially I was worried that these were too girly, too clichéd. Are they good role models for my kids? But I quickly learnt why they love them. They are exciting, strong, positive role models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So together, we’re exploring different films and characters. Like My Little Pony: Equestrian Girls. This is an alternative universe where the ponies are human girls who form a rock band, have magical powers and work together to defeat evil dragons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They enjoy “boy stuff” too, like Marvel and Transformers. But it feels very segregated still. Boys toys and girls toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think companies like Disney and Marvel are slowly creating more diverse role models for kids to look up to though. Apparently, the next Iron Man film will star a 15-year-old black girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Star Wars is another good example of franchise that’s being updated. Princess Leia is pretty strong characted in the early films, but in one of them she’s tied up as Jabba’s sex slave, so I’m not going to watch that with my kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the new star wars, Leia is a General. And one of the lead characters, Rey, is 😮 a woman! I can’t wait to watch these films with my kids when they’re a bit older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new Star Wars film coming out too. It’s called Rogue One, and it also stars 😱 a woman! Apparently this is a genuine YouTube comment about the trailer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’m not sexist but Star Wars is about men, men fighting to save the universe. If women can do the same as men, what’s the point? I won’t be seeing this. If you need me I’ll be watching anime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a typical example of the way men react online when gender roles are reversed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trolls have been out in force over the new Ghostbusters film too. But look how happy these 2 girls are. This is what representation in the media can do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://benjystanton.github.io/assets/ghostbusters-representation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kristen Wiig meeting 2 girls dressed in Ghostbusters fancy dress.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The olympics have been full of men saying embarrassing things too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such as John Inverdale, saying that Andy Murray was “the first person ever to win two Olympic tennis gold medals”, completely forgetting that Venus and Serena Williams have won four each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/beggie_smalls/status/762545510930677760&quot;&gt;bloke on Twitter, mansplaining to olympic athlete&lt;/a&gt; Annemiek van Vleuten after her horrendous crash by saying: “the first lesson in bicycling, keep your bike steady… whether fast or slow”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly as bad as mansplaining is manspreading. Guys have a look down at your legs now and if you’re manspreading then do the people either side of you a favour and close them up a little. You’re not that big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://benjystanton.github.io/assets/manspreading.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man on a train sitting with his legs very far apart.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit: WNYC New York Public Radio (CC BY-NC 2.0)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if like me, you’re keen to be a better man then I recommend following &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/manwhohasitall&quot;&gt;@manwhohasitall on twitter&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an account that takes headlines from trashy women’s magazines then aims them at men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Men! Is having it all really possible? Kids, relationship, beach hair, imaginative picnic ideas AND a PH balanced intimate area?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It highlights the absurd way that women are treated by the media sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m hear today as a sign of solidarity to say: “My name is Benjy and I’m a feminist”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and guys, it’s okay if you want to watch pink, sparkly things sometimes. It doesn’t mean you’re any less of a man. It doesn’t mean you’re gay. It doesn’t mean anything. Unless you want it to. Just relax and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://benjystanton.github.io/assets/glitter-force.gif&quot; alt=&quot;A pink super hero draws a huge heart in the sky.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;update&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably look back on this and cringe. Being a feminist is hard and I’ve probably revealed some of inner prejudices here without realising it. If you have any feedback, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjystanton&quot;&gt;let me know over on twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 12:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/things-my-little-girls-have-taught-me-about-feminism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/things-my-little-girls-have-taught-me-about-feminism/</guid>
        
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
        <category>talk</category>
        
        <category>family</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User experience (UX) designer skills</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A list of skills needed to be a user experience designer, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://centercentre.com/&quot;&gt;Centre Centre&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uxward/status/763797497307246592/photo/1&quot;&gt;Brandon Ward shared this list on twitter&lt;/a&gt;. It was shared as an image so I decided to write it up as text here for prosperity.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technical-skills&quot;&gt;Technical skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front-end development&lt;/strong&gt;: coding valid HTML, CSS, JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual design&lt;/strong&gt;: understanding the use of colour, grid, layout and typography&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile integration&lt;/strong&gt;: creating consistent experiences through responsive layouts, touch interactions and input techniques&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project management&lt;/strong&gt;: incorporating iterative design, agile practices and software development life cycles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information architecture&lt;/strong&gt;: planning experiences through site mapping, modelling and wireframes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interaction design&lt;/strong&gt;: building flow, form design, micro-interactions and transition animations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copywriting and content strategy&lt;/strong&gt;: writing microcopy, content modelling and content inventories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User research&lt;/strong&gt;: conducting field research, usability studies,  research synthesis and data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;soft-skills&quot;&gt;Soft skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenting&lt;/strong&gt;: sharing thoughts an design concepts with peers and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facilitating&lt;/strong&gt;: extracting design requirements and project direction from peers and stakeholders, while prompting a shared understanding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critiquing&lt;/strong&gt;: receiving, giving and training peers and stakeholders with constructive feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storytelling&lt;/strong&gt;: communicating and affirming to peers and stakeholders how decisions were made, how principles were arrived at, and how the design will improve the lives of the users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sketching&lt;/strong&gt;: communicating emerging ideas quickly and exploring problem space with peers and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leadership&lt;/strong&gt;: providing vision, direction and passion to peers and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 17:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-skills/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/user-experience-ux-designer-skills/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should designers design content?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my experience, interaction and visual designers are often relied upon to write the words used in an interface (also known as microcopy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers are also in a good position to improve longer types of content like blog articles. Remember, this content might have been written by someone who is not experienced at writing for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I think it’s the responsibility of designers to improve a website’s content (unless you are lucky enough to work with a great content designer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/content-design/what-is-content-design&quot;&gt;What is content design?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 16:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/should-designers-design-content/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/should-designers-design-content/</guid>
        
        
        <category>content</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The first UK Government accessibility meet-up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in May I went to the first UK Government accessibility meet-up. It was organised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dugboticus&quot;&gt;Alistair Duggin&lt;/a&gt; and his accessibility team at GDS (Government Digital Service).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://leadin.fi/blog/uk-government-accessibility-meet-up/&quot;&gt;read my meetup notes over on the Leadin blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 19:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/uk-government-accessibility-meet-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/uk-government-accessibility-meet-up/</guid>
        
        
        <category>accessibility</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>meetup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New ABCs of Research by Ben Schneiderman</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Working at Swansea University has its benefits. I was invited along to a lecture by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benbendc&quot;&gt;Ben Schneiderman&lt;/a&gt; recently, one of the authors of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Designing-User-Interface-Human-Computer-Interaction/dp/0321537351&quot;&gt;Designing the User Interface&lt;/a&gt;. Here are my rough notes from his talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-book-the-new-abcs-of-research&quot;&gt;New Book: The New ABCs of Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben was promoting his new book &lt;a href=&quot;https://global.oup.com/academic/product/the-new-abcs-of-research-9780198758839?cc=gb&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;The New ABCs of Research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-research-context&quot;&gt;New research context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old model of research needs to be updated, because we are facing new challenges:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immense challenges in the 21st Century (e.g. healthcare)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New tools like the web, social media, visual communication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raised ambitions and expectations about what can be accomplished in a short period of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;research-strategies&quot;&gt;Research strategies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the principles and tips from his talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;work on real world problems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;work with actual practitioners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we are witnessing a growing movement in design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;design is as important as science and engineering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;talk to real users and have empathy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the best way to promote your ideas is to write well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;publish in open, accessible, free ways&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;form teams with diverse individuals and organisations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do something small soon… it’s the path to larger things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be social and be engaged with the wider community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“do something small soon… it’s the path to larger things”&lt;br /&gt;
Ben Schneiderman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 17:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/the-new-abcs-of-research/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/the-new-abcs-of-research/</guid>
        
        
        <category>conferences</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Port80 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My notes from the brilliant Port80 web design conference, including talks from Gavin Davies, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalaccessibilitycentre.org/&quot;&gt;Digital Accessibility Centre&lt;/a&gt;, Helen Clark and Ash Nolan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;louise-howellshttpstwittercomsupertastycake&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/supertastycake&quot;&gt;Louise Howells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-so-serious-running-a-team-hack-day&quot;&gt;Why so serious? Running a team hack day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Louise is a Professional Services Manager at Zengenti&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;happy working environments are good for staff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;good offices need breakout zones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zengenti call their annual hackathon “Lockdown”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;step away from the day job and do something different&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;teams created digital and physical products like:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a games room in the basement&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a BBQ area&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a website that listed design conferences&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;helps to foster a community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;staff started up book clubs and pool clubs afterwards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it encouraged staff to do job swaps and learn about different areas of the business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://supertastycake.wordpress.com/2016/04/30/running-a-hack-day-team/&quot;&gt;blog post about running a hack day team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gavin-davieshttpstwittercomgavduk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gavd_uk&quot;&gt;Gavin Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-build-tools&quot;&gt;Using build tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gavin is an automation engineer/coder at Radify&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;software is advancing at a scary pace&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it’s important to understand things conceptually first&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it’s about workflow not particular tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improve your workflow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reduce tedious, manual tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get feedback sooner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use Grunt or Gulp (it doesn’t matter which) to automate your asset pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use linters to highlight bad code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;optimise images and minify code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use gulp-rsync to deploy automatically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use source maps to debug your Sass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yeoman can help get up and running quickly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://radify.io/blog/using-build-tools/&quot;&gt;Blog post and PDF about using front-end build tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fred-heathhttpstwittercomfredatbootstrap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FredAtBootstrap&quot;&gt;Fred Heath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-uncertainty-principle&quot;&gt;The uncertainty principle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how do we deal with uncertainty?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;why do projects fail?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it’s hard (impossible) to estimate project time and cost&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cushioning is when you give a client the worst case estimate and double it, this is bad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;telling a client you don’t know how long things will take is not much better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter SCRUM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 week sprints, then show client&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;product backlog &amp;gt; sprint planning &amp;gt; sprint backlog &amp;gt; sprint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;behaviour driven development (BDD) is “outside in” development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stakeholders define features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;features are like user stories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tools: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cucumber.io/&quot;&gt;cucumber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write scenarios for features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;scenarios are like examples e.g. show special offers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;these should be in plain English&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;then write a step definition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sprint planning &amp;gt; define steps (flesh out plan) &amp;gt; do the work &amp;gt; show and tell &amp;gt; retrospective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gavin-evanshttpstwittercomgavinaevans-and-jaime-purvis&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gavinaevans&quot;&gt;Gavin Evans&lt;/a&gt; and Jaime Purvis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;designing-accessible-websites&quot;&gt;Designing accessible websites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;accessibility is about not creating barriers right from the design stage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developers need to use the right mark-up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;follow web standards and WCAG 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;user testing with actual users with disabilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tips for better mark-up
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;provide alternative text for visual content&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;consider users who don’t use a mouse&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;use structure and logical hierarchy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;don’t suppress zoom&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;display:none&lt;/code&gt; hides it from everyone, so be careful&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;always style up hover, active, focus&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use tools to check understanding level of your content&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;html &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;track&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element to add text or captions to videos (webVTT)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;bad error handling is bad&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;don’t rely on placeholder text only in forms inputs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.html5accessibility.com/&quot;&gt;www.html5accessibility.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use ARIA roles for sectioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to use iOS Voiceover
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;two finger tap stops speech&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;swipe left and right to go to next item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;twist hand to choose different elements&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;swipe down with 2 fingers to read on&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;details&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in Firefox with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nvaccess.org/&quot;&gt;NVDA&lt;/a&gt; skips over it completely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;avoid cluttered designs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mobile versions of sites are generally better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the less content the better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;label properly, be descriptive but concise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dynamic sites are hard to navigate, if something changes make sure focus changes too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andy-clarkehttpstwittercommalarkey&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/malarkey&quot;&gt;Andy Clarke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;designing-imaginative-grid-systems&quot;&gt;Designing imaginative grid systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;web design is boring right now&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://everyfuckingwebsite.com/&quot;&gt;everyfuckingwebsite.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bland.ly/#blandly&quot;&gt;bland.ly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(too busy listening to make proper notes sorry)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/malarkey/designing-imaginative-grid-systems-port-80-newport&quot;&gt;Slides for Andy’s talk: Designing imaginative grid systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;helen-clarkhttpstwittercomlittlehelli&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/littlehelli&quot;&gt;Helen Clark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-and-inclusive-design&quot;&gt;Open and inclusive design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beware stealth stakeholders, these are senior staff who pop up at the end of projects and try to change things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;work in the open&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;document everything done on the project (on Tumblr for example)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;speak to customers (end users) to discover user stories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get honest, impartial feedback (users might lie if staff are running the research sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;speak to staff (at their place of work) especially front line staff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create a list of priories based on this research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clarkcx.com/advice/paper-prototypes-what-are-they-and-why-use-them&quot;&gt;paper prototypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;feedback can be applied beyond the website, so share your research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;risks of working openly?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;research should uncover problems not solutions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;working in the open can make some people uncomfortable (it shows the behind the scenes, messy, ugly bits)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;good research means you can justify design decisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/&quot;&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;build iteratively&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;people’s needs first&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;design with data&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;open by default&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ensure everyone can participate&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.growthdrivendesign.com/&quot;&gt;Growth Driven Design&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;launching the website shouldn’t be the end&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;launch a basic site first&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;build the must-haves, and leave the nice-to-haves until later&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;then do continuous improvement&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beware: clients might block access to users if they feel left out of research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;immerse the client in the design team, then both can communicate with the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ashley-nolanhttpstwittercomashnolan&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AshNolan_&quot;&gt;Ashley Nolan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;developing-for-the-unknown&quot;&gt;Developing for the unknown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ash is front end dev at Just Eat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no docs or commenting leads to legacy code straight away&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;put the right things in place from the start: structure and workflow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;workflow
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;grunt and gulp can act as self documentation to show new devs what workflows exists&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;grunt or gulp, it doesn’t matter&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;create common workflows: e.g. Sass, linting, minifying&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;documentation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;good commenting&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;style guides&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“programs should be written for people to read and incidentally for machines to understand”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;describe what components do and where they’re used&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;style guide and component library
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;look for patterns&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;reuse them across website&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;organise CSS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;start small and extend&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;components only worry about themselves&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://smacss.com/&quot;&gt;SMACSS&lt;/a&gt; by Snook&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naming schemes: BEM or SUIT
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;be consistent&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;show relationship between class names&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;BEM: Block, elements, modifier&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://trykickoff.com/learn/css.html#namingscheme&quot;&gt;BEM naming scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://trykickoff.com/statix/&quot;&gt;Statix, a reusable snippets tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Static site generators &lt;a href=&quot;http://assemble.io/&quot;&gt;Assemble&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate your concerns
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;decouple CSS classes from JS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;hook JS into data attributes or IDs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;look into &lt;a href=&quot;http://postcss.org/&quot;&gt;PostCSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whatever we create should be built to last&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://port80events.co.uk/event/port-80-2016/&quot;&gt;Official Port80 2016 website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/seanuk&quot;&gt;Photos from Port80 2016 by Sean Johnson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mearso.co.uk/sketchnotes/port80-2016/&quot;&gt;Sketch notes from Port80 2016 by Kevin Mears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 11:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/port-80-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/port-80-2016/</guid>
        
        
        <category>conferences</category>
        
        <category>front-end</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The last ten percent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At my first design job, we used to talk about the last 10%. This was the time that we’d set aside at the end of a project, to sit down and review the website together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d compare the (almost) finished website against the mock-ups, the navigation diagrams and the content plan. We’d stop &lt;em&gt;making&lt;/em&gt; the site and try to &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt; the site. We solved content issues, white space issues, typography issues, interaction issues. We were designing in the browser, although we didn’t call it that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We were designing in the browser, although we didn’t call it that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we’d even be shifting pixels about. Yeah I know pixel perfection is an unrealistic goal, but if every element is 5 pixels out, then the overall effect can be a design that feels &lt;a href=&quot;http://us5.campaign-archive2.com/?u=7e093c5cf4&amp;amp;id=564702bd96&quot;&gt;disjointed and unbalanced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would always take longer than 10% of the project budget to get this done. But the effect was usually huge. It turned a site from an average one into a great one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the downfall of that business was that later on, we tried to cut out this process. We tried to compartmentalise our individual skills. We tried to force a waterfall approach and to become more streamlined. We stopped allowing for the final 10%. This meant that we shipped websites that weren’t finished, even though we had ticked every box in “our process”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time I held on the the crazy idea that better planning, better skills and more experience would lead to projects that didn’t need this review process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever you call it — the last 10%, testing, proofing, quality assurance — this is when the real work starts. It’s much more agile and much more realistic. It’s how really good products and services are designed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the last 10% usually takes up about 90% of the budget.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 21:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/the-last-ten-percent/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://benjystanton.github.io/blog/the-last-ten-percent/</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>process</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
